Poetry
On the Seabed
We are at the bottom of a deep sea
A desert of words extends from directly below
While waves of expression surfaced far above
We can’t breathe freely
We can’t even move our mouths
We are at the bottom of a deep sea
Whatever was available, was enough
The desire to express oneself has no bounds
We are at the bottom of a deep sea
At the bottom of an even deeper sea
Floating, with a body seemingly crushed by the water pressure
Floating, trying to reach for the moonlight on the water
We are whales
At the bottom of an even deeper sea
Swallowing the krill of words
While drawing and swimming deep in the sea of imagination
Always
Looking for something that’s missing
March 31st,
Tokyo Garden Theatre
We are Yorushika.
｢Evening Calm, Some Place, Fireworks｣
♪～Yuunagi, Bou, Hana Madoi
Elma
Before the seasons turned to summer,
I wrote about the fireworks in my heart
The night is about to fall,
and the day after tomorrow is all that I see
I’ll say it one more time
I’ll recall that one August day
They’re the only things I can never speak enough of
The two measures ring out from my guitar
This song is 380 characters long
I wrote rock and roll songs
And only sang of that summer
“Goodbye” alone is not enough
I want to sing of glowing red days to you
Just remembering will never be enough
I wait for a summer with swimming flowers,
and you turn into words
I wrote of the fireworks in that summer
so I wouldn’t forget
The us in my memories are like ghosts you can’t see anytime but at night
There’s nothing good left
This world was difficult for me to understand
It’s just full of things you never taught me
We played piano in that hall
That cafe doesn’t exist anymore
I want to kill the two we talked so badly about
If you were here, you’d definitely laugh at that
How things are now still isn’t enough
I want us to be lost in a breeze obfuscated by flowers
The mere act of remembering is painful
I dream that summer will come
And with that, a hole opened up in my heart
Singing songs alone won’t be enough
I want to sing of glowing red days to you
I want to know what a beautiful night is like
I wait for a summer of fireworks
I am illuminated by the moonlight
｢August, That Place, Moonlight｣
♪～Hachigatsu, Bou, Tsukiakari
That’s Why I Gave Up On Music
I don’t need anything
My heart became irritated; as I walked, it got hard to breathe
When I first ran away from my part-time job
I didn’t care anymore about music or life or anything
The number of things that annoyed me just kept increasing
On that August day, in that place, there was moonlight, I was flying on my bike
The elevated bridge at Higashifushimi, Kodaira, Fujimidoori and the shopping area
The night wind tickled my nose, and the pain in my heart wasn’t real–
I understood that; I pretended to understand that
I’m the worst, I’m the worst
Everything about me is the worst
I wanted something concrete to remember you by
I don’t want to let you become just a memory!
I’m the worst, I’m the worst
There’s no point to just feeling good
Because these lyrics, too, are the worst
If my life could end at twenty-seven, rock and roll saved me
By saying “Stop thinking so much! You’ll die anyway”
I don’t need anything, even you
My heart became irritated
I laughed until my throat went dry
The first time I sold my heart
I didn’t care anymore if it was pride or heart disease
I bowed my head even to people that annoyed me
On that August day, in that place, I strode through the scenery of the past
The street vendors of Stockholm, Kiruna, the cobbled streets of Gamla Stan
You were the only thing shut away inside my heart
Even the blue of the sky is just my imagination
I was smiling; my face just stayed that way
I’m the worst, I’m too arrogant; you’re as greedy as anyone else
There’s no point in dramatic songs or loves, it just makes you look like a fool
I knew, I knew
Your life was your own
However much I shouted “It’s the worst”
That’s right, of course that’s right
Rock ‘n’ roll flows through the world beyond
While hymns and stuff aren’t that popular
Because there’s no god
I don’t know anything about sins or mistakes or crimes or suicide or wars or minorities
It’s the worst, it’s the worst; to leave was arrogance
I want to agree with you on everything
But that would be deceiving you, Elma
It’s the worst, it’s the worst; I can’t help this affection
I want to mourn myself in the dramatic night
It’s the worst, it’s the worst; these words are just redundant
Your life is moonlight
I could never say it was commonplace
It’s the worst, it’s the worst; I can’t help being laughed at
These lyrics that sound nice but mean nothing are the worst
If my life could end at twenty-seven, rock and roll saved me
By saying “Stop thinking so much! You’ll die anyway”
The present, love, the past, dreams, memories,
humming, light-colored eyes, night mist,
Tenderness, pain, flowers, melancholy, that summer, this song,
Hypocrisy, the night wind, lies, you, myself, the blue sky–I don’t need any of them
Poetry
In Sekimachi
I hated boring things
That's why I hate myself
I'm gradually getting used to living in Sekimachi
But I can't get used to a life without you
I can't even afford to buy flowers
Frankly, I'm tired of the part-time work that I do for a living
Reality is a swamp
I'd live on music alone if I could
But it seems I'm missing something
I was watching the sunset
I've been walking for a while
Fujimi-dori is a shopping district
The rotary in front of the station, a madder red
On my way back from my part-time work, I heard a song
In my head, it resounded
The piano you played, resounded
If I only had a single year left to live
What would I do now
The value of one's life is in the way it ends
If that was the case, then I'd like to preserve the meaning of my birth
But I want something special
There's nothing more boring than a novel with a sloppy ending
That's it.
I'll turn my life into a work of art
Elma, I'll make something
I can leave behind for you
Somewhere in a faraway land
In the places where I traveled
I'll write poems
And I'll send you back those letters and poems
This is the year
This one year is my entire life
I want to create a work of art with my life
I want to draw something that I can leave behind for you
I've already decided on the title of the piece
"That's Why I Gave Up On Music"
I was watching the sunset
I've been walking for a while
Fujimi-dori is a shopping district
The rotary in front of the station, a madder red
On my way back from my part-time work, I heard a song
In my head, it resounded
The piano you played, resounded
｢Deep Indigo｣
♪～Ai Nijou
That’s Why I Gave Up On Music
The scenery doesn’t change; on a faded afternoon
I’m lying in the deep indigo beneath the overpass
I hear a single clap for my blank-page life
I was singing about my own emptiness today, as usual
So things wouldn’t change,
I wrote a story starring you in my notebook
My gas and water being cut off, society, and the news are all someone else’s problem
Look, my life is like ink
The dream I had when I was young gets closer to its expiration date as I get older
Though I just, I just look up at the clouds
As usual, they flow through my field of vision
In the distant night sky I looked up at, flowers swam
So many that it could be mistaken for spring
As if I’d just lost sight of you
I looked down so I wouldn’t trip
Life is made of nothing but compromises
I don’t believe in hearts or fate or love songs or life
After all, if you can’t sell something it has no value
I intentionally discarded the present I dreamed of,
and now I’m lying here waiting for its expiration date
Behind my eyelids, I just, I just saw
An imagined, distant vision of you
In my notebook, flowers swim in the corner of a faded night
One more is in my eye
Life is just one compromise after another
I learned that pretty fast
Elma,
it’s you
You alone are my music
There are only eighty more characters in this song
Because maybe the only value of a life is in the way it ends
I just, I just picture you
As even the indigo filling my vision is blurred
In the distant sky I looked up at, flowers swam
Deep indigo covers my eyes
It’s just, it’s just…
In the distant sky I looked up at, you are cooling off
As if you were just swimming in the night
｢Dance of God｣
♪～Kamisama no Dance
Elma
To forget is horrible right?
Will it turn into happiness?
Something devoid of colour bloomed
It bloomed in that summer without you
Not wanting people to laugh at me
I look at the ground as to scare them off
Can something more important than my heart even exist?
A madder red chased the ever bright evening
Neglecting to dye you
Pass by me so that you can’t see me
But please don’t go
We who know not the face of god
Are able to go anywhere
Hey, we’re ugly to the core
But the world belongs to us
It’s fine if it’s just through music right?
We don’t have to walk in step with the rest
Weren’t you the one who taught me that?
It doesn’t matter to me, let’s go some place far away right now
In a place unbeknownst to anyone,
we’ll look for the moonlight.
“Flowers without a name are pretty” and all that jazz
Doesn’t really matter to me
But that phrase of yours is rubbing off on me
Right below my throat is where you exist
Only when you’ve thrown away my words,
my life, my everything, can music be made
How can you not understand what it costs?
A madder red chased the ever bright evening
Neglecting to dye me
One day, time will overtake everything
But don’t disappear
We, who know not the face of the gods
Want the whole world
Hey, give me your all your memories, you’re ugly to the core
If this world’s values aren’t set
Then it’s okay to hurt each other, right?
Weren’t you the one who didn’t teach me that?
It doesn’t matter to me, let’s go to some place far away right now
In a place no one is looking at,
we’ll do our best imitation of living.
Dancing with ugly faces
While our chests ache
The gods, who know not our faces
Are able to go anywhere
Hey, if you say that words make up the world, then the world is ours
To forget is horrible right?
Will we be able to become happy that way?
Aren’t you the one who made me think this way?
That may be so, but regardless I’ll go some where far away right now
And look for moonlight in a place unbeknownst to anyone
｢False Night｣
♪～Yoru Magai
That’s Why I Gave Up On Music
Who cares about singing faithfully
I want to live taking it easier than other people,
I don’t want to work hard
Walking along with my head down, not realizing how blue the sky is
I’m stuck gazing only at your picture
My hollow heart set out for a stroll in the sunset town
The part of it that’s a lie slowly and heavily growing more taut than the barrel of a gun
Each life is a machine gun,
blow it all away, more!
Hey, even the heart’s taken away, with just one parting word
I want to erase these sad things
I want to erase these happy things too
I want to erase my heart
One’s enough for you, just wanna put a hole in you
"Nameless flowers are beautiful", who cares about that
I wanna erase this obnoxiously bright heart,
I don’t want to go to work
Talking to people with my head down, I can’t understand people’s feelings
I’m stuck gazing only at your picture
In the middle of the live bar, I’m faithfully singing
Having the nerve to sing songs not for money,
it’s idiotic, isn’t it?
Life is a machine gun, that’s what I’m getting at
Hey, sing on every refrain, with all of that throat
I want to erase these painful songs
I want to erase these kind songs too
Just listening hurts
One’s enough for me.
Each life is a machine gun, blow it all away, more!
Hey, laugh that it’s painful, with one parting word
I want to become a memory for you,
that lives by passing it onto the next generation,
I feel like just watching hurts
Just one is enough,
once is enough for you
I want to penetrate through
Poetry
About the Rainy Town
The rainy season in June is something that I can't wait to see a bit more of
I sat alone on the rainy terrace of the café
It's an unpopular table
Writing poems, sipping cappuccino
Until the rainy season ends, this is my special seat
The papers that I threw away, rolls as the wind blew
One of the crumpled poems, rolls down
You picked it up and stared blankly at it
I looked at your profile and thought of something
Paintings unknown to the Museum of Arts
The sound of a piano, leaking from a house as if it was the rays of twilight
A beauty that peeks through the roadside flowers
The sunset of a clear day
Sea breeze and Moonlight
I want to be that
I want to be the midsummer clouds
I want that beauty to dwell from the poems that I write with my fingers
I want to be the colors of the sunrise
I want to be the mirror that reflects it
I want to be those words
Walking through the rainy city
While only thinking about one thing
The scenery changes like a flash from a camera
The scenery keeps changing
I thought about what to write today
While picking up the pieces of papers that overflowed from my bag
I raised my face to look up
I am...
on a café terrace, dripping with rain
｢Rain and Cappuccino｣
♪～Ame to Cappuccino
Elma
My words that had faded to grey are now a color like cappuccino
Enough of the excuses, leave them by the window
There are too many to count
My heart that had faded to grey is now a color like cappuccino
Enough of the excuses, I’ll gulp down cappuccino
And pretend to be an idiot
The rain flows as if indecisive
We drown in the flowers storming around us
So you won’t fade away, I keep this memory–
I hope,
I hope
you don’t overflow
The beach awaits the waves; a red evening sun shines
They’re reflected in the window
Visby in August, the roar of the sea
I wait in vain for a single sea breeze
The white of the flowers that swam in the summer, the evening rain
Drown in the flowing night
So no one will fade away, keep this flower–
I hope,
I hope
you’ll stick it to the inside of your heart
Things have been strange for a long time
I just want someone to tell me one way to live
I have no way to pay for it anymore
But if it’s too hard to answer, a single word would be enough
I don’t understand
I seriously don’t get it at all
The rain flows as if indecisive
We drown in the flowers storming around us
So you won’t fade away, I write this song–
I hope,
I hope
you haven’t forgotten it even now
Another summer comes to an end, and I hold a single flower in my heart,
Flowing beneath my eyelids
So you won’t fade away, I wrote this song
I hope,
I hope
you don’t overflow
｢In June, I Write About the Town After the Rain｣
♪～Rokugatsu wa Ameagari no Machi o Kaku
That’s Why I Gave Up On Music
The ultramarine town is reflected in the window
The early summer rain flows through the drainpipe
In a daze, I’m watching as
A single drop falls, falls
The shape of my heart is rectangular
It lives only in this sheet of paper
While you exist only in the supernate
Floating on the surface of the lyrics that I wrote one after another
It’s all so pointless
It’s just stupid
I want to see something that’s not rational
Because I’m sure it would be unfortunate only to forget
The strong scent of rain
Move your mouth
Trace it with your fingers
Sew it up with words
Wait for me in that town
The street lights dance to the sound of the rain
I pass twilight and turn at the corner,
A one-person parade of footsteps
The clouds that wait for the summer are a misty blue
My life now is i^2
Subtracting you left me below zero
I can only see you in my memories
In the aftermath of the June rain
Scribbling down even your smiling face
Digging deep into my heart
I knew that it was unconvincing
Though it’s unfortunate only to forget even the strong scent of rain
I wish I could’ve seen your face
When you read my letters
Written about that summer
Everything’s so trivial
Getting involved with others is too much trouble
Even putting my thoughts into words is a pain
In the end, was it always only you?
It’s all so goddamn pointless
It’s just stupid
I always knew it wasn’t rational
I’m always writing about the rainy town
And the strong scent of rain
Moving your heart
Yearning
Sewing things up like this
I’m waiting in that town
｢After the Rain｣
♪～Ame Haruru
Elma
Finally, the rain fell
I’ve been thinking about this blue for a while now
The sound of my heart was clear
It’s a sky where I didn’t need anything other than words
I’ve been asleep up until that day
Unwilling to take a step, making excuses
I’ll take the blue of the town you lived in for a while that’s bluer than I imagined and
Sing it out for a while. This life is you.
It’s always been you, everything is you, a deep indigo blue
Even if you turn into words, these memories you left behind alone was dyed a far aquamarine
I wanna write about it more, this love song that won’t grow cold for a while
Another summer without you will come
Finally, the rain stopped
You surely painted this down once
Ever since that day that cleared up the sound of my heart
You’ve been waiting for me
Unable to form words I laugh, and so you’re none the wiser
Please erase it, please erase it all
Your voice, words, and love songs
A curtain sways in the pale aquamarine colour that covered my eyes
I want to feel this love song more, I want to feel it more
I want to feel the blue of the summer without you as well
A white curtain swayed
It softly swayed, it swayed to me, and touched upon our love
Even if you turn into words, those songs you left behind and
That longing won’t disappear, they haven’t been able to disappear
That unmistakable colour hasn’t been able to fade
So sing it out, this life is all you
It’s all you, the colour of love that hasn’t been able to disappear
It’s the pale aquamarine colour that covered my eyes
It swayed as if it remembers
I want to write of it more, this love song that won’t fade out
Another summer without you will come around
Poetry
In Visby
I was searching for the place closest to heaven
Somewhere along the way, I found myself walking through a seaside town
I made my way through a back alley,
and when I took a right,
I began to hear the faint sound of ocean waves
I saw a cat mewling in the shadow of a flowerpot
It gave off the illusion that the summer was coming to an end
I turned my head towards the crying, entranced by it
The cat nuzzled against me with its flexible body
And then it disappeared into the summer shadows
Without realizing it, a bicycle approached from behind me,
the owner glaring at me as he approached
I surrendered the path to him
With that, I finally had a clear view of the road I had traversed
Far away,
At the church far beyond the hill I had climbed,
I had prayed that morning
When I remembered that moment,
I-I mourned myself
I'm searching for the place closest to heaven.
｢Let's Dance｣
♪～Odorou ze
That’s Why I Gave Up On Music
Ah, with a heart that’s clearer than transparent,
I’m laughing at the world
Ah, thinking back to when I chose music
I feel I was such an...
...idiot then
Everything I want to tell you–
This song,
even my voice–
Has turned into the wind and vanished with the bubbles
So I want to throw away this synesthesia-like sentiment
If it’s okay for me to do this, if you want to know,
I won’t hide anything anymore
From now on I’ll dance...
just a little
Ah, I want to give up on being human
That’s right, nothing holds any interest for me anymore
Ah, thinking back on when I showed off that guitar I was so proud of
I want to crush the person...
I was back then
Everything I want to tell you–
The summer, the winter — beyond tomorrow
It’s all become ash and disappeared in an instant
So I’m throwing away this emotion I lost long ago
If it’s okay with you, if you just want to forget
I won’t hesitate anymore
I’ll dance like this until dawn
Ah, I’ve given up on music
If I write about you just as you were in my memory, with no changes at all,
Then there won’t be a single thing left that I want to do
Nothing comes to mind
Because the days when I knew you are past
Somehow I want to capture this emotion I want to catch up with in a song
If my life now is painful, because I’ve had enough of the excuses,
Ah, well, I’ll dance — look
It’s become the wind, it’s vanished with the bubbles
No matter what, I’ll throw away this sensation I can’t explain
If it’s okay for me to do this, if you want to know,
I won’t hide anything anymore
From now on, just a little,
Like this, just a little, I’ll dance
｢Walk｣
♪～Aruku
Elma
Today, I felt the sensation
Like I was starting to die
Just waiting for tomorrow
While I looked down on the changing seasons
Might as well, I think
I’ve come far enough
Let’s put an end to pretending not to know anything
I walked along the stone pavement to make sure
I hung my head low while I walked
so that I wouldn’t see anything
I walk in the town you journeyed through
Without reason, it started coming out of my mouth
Until yesterday, I had been asleep
Merely existing without knowing a thing
That’s just how it is
Today, I hallucinated
That I was alive
I’d be fine if it was just in my delusions
I wish you could live on for me
I write only of sad-like songs
With emerald green trailing your cheeks
I actually knew everything all along
That it was the end of summer
Reading the clouds that passed above
The town I walk in where I have my head held high is in my memories
I move to eat your words
What can you see in my mouth?
Even now, these eyes are asleep
I was just looking at you without seeing anything
So that I could wander around
You’re there in front of that hill
What can you see from your side?
Only words reach my mouth
I existed without knowing anything
That’s all there is
Even now, Amy
｢A Hole Opened Up in My Heart｣
♪～Kokoro ni Ana ga Aita
Elma
A small hole opened up
Right in the middle of my chest
A night-imitating twilight
Painted the town
I want to forget
But in the blue sky that buries my mind that wants to forget, I only see you
That’s why a hole opened up in my heart
My heartbeat pounded as if to fill it in
When I opened my mouth to talk to you
What came out was mostly excuses
That’s why a hole opened up in my heart
I thought only the falling rain was warm
I’m fixing, fixing, fixing
My faceless self alone
It’s like sleeping in a forest
where a hole has gradually opened in the light coming through the leaves
Deep like the bottom of the sea
Deep, like sleeping still more
deep,
deep
Until moonlight is seen in the depths of eyes covered up by the deep darkness of night
I opened up a hole in your heart
What does music matter, anyway?
Just open your mouth
If you stay silent, you’ll never get the things you deserve
There are so many things I want to forget
Only resignation comes out of my mouth
Stumbling, stumbling, falling,
feeling only the cold ground
I want to write about my life, which I wanted to make into your life
It’s because of the songs you left behind
It’s all music’s fault
I imitated the way you spoke
I copied the way you lived
But though I tried to erase myself so that nothing of me would remain
It remains still
I clung to your words
Which nestled in the hole in my heart
But it’s different now
I don’t ever want to hear “goodbye”
There are so many things I want to forget
From now on, only I will grow older
Growing colder, growing colder
A hole opened up in my heart
Your words opened a hole in my heart
I understand now
“You alone are my music,” Amy
That’s why a hole opened up in my heart
You were nestled on the other side of it
It will never go back to the way it was
It’s just a hole that’s spreading, spreading, spreading
Just me, with a hole in my heart
｢Parade｣
♪～Parade
That’s Why I Gave Up On Music
Inside my body,
right below my throat,
if there’s a heart then you
must be there
I’ve known for a long time
That as I got older I would even forget your face
Because I want to know the moment that words are able to form inside my body, in my throat
If the dawn comes like this…
I hope that my memories don’t dry out
I hope that I don’t lose this song
Don’t forget, for just a little longer,
The lonely parade
I’ve thought for a long time that
Gods might reside in your fingertips
Since before today, before yesterday,
since a long, long time past
I’ve known that
Inside my body, right below my throat
Are the days when I’ve only been imitating your song
I hope that I don’t forget
The temperature of this moment in which you’re not here
With memories that I hope won’t dry out
With this song that I haven’t been able to forget
Just a little bit more, for just a little longer
I’ll make a lonely parade
｢Seabed, Moonlight｣
♪～Kaitei, Tsukiakari
Elma
｢Just Sorrow｣
♪～Yuu Ichijou
Elma
I think I’m at the bottom of a river
A single breath constricts my throat
Watching the air escape my mouth for a few seconds,
my feet finally touched the ground
I felt the gentle bubbles
For a long time
For a long, long, long time now
Just by chasing after you
I’ve wanted to talk only about things beyond my control
The water lilies floated along the water, transparent
If it's only a little more certain than a mirage already, that’d be great
I’d be fine if you did the bare minimum
I’d be fine if it was something we aimed for
At this rate, I’d be fine with going anywhere, so let’s run away
I think I’m at the bottom of a river
My wet eardrums feel ticklish
I didn’t want to ask about hopes, the future, tomorrow, or anything really
Those questions died quickly just by seeing the beauty of the bubbles escaping my mouth
For a long time
For a long, long, long time now
Just by being enchanted by it
I wanted to find something more important than my heart
Words are cruel, above the water they seem transparent
Hey, I’m looking for something prettier than how to act properly
It’s fine to forget about it though, so let’s run away
I don’t need this self of mine
I don’t need anything
I don’t need money, or fame, or love, or recognition — nothing
I want to go far away right now,
Touch the outside of these memories,
And listen to your songs once more
For a long time
For a long, long, long time now
Just by chasing after you
I’ve wanted to sing only about things I can’t control
The water lilies floated along the water, looking transparent
If it's only a little more certain than a mirage already, that’d be great
At this rate, I’d be fine with going anywhere
The truth is that I’ve only been wanting to leave everything behind and run away
This life is transparent, above the water, seemingly transparent
I’ve had enough. If it’s only a little more certain than a mirage, I’d be fine with it
I’d be fine if you did the bare minimum
I’d be fine if it was something we aimed for
At this rate, I’d be fine with going anywhere, so let’s run away
｢Nautilus｣
♪～Nautilus
Elma
When the alarm clock rang, I finally woke up
The flu I had yesterday doesn’t seem real anymore
I think of going out, but, ah, the forecast says it looks like rain
Well, I couldn’t go anyway because it’s still dark
A dry throat, a hurting heart–
all these human things are getting in my way
Lift your head at the speed of the farewell
Someday dawn will finally break
Come on, try and open your eyes
Because I’ve pictured your sleepy eyes so many times
I finally decided to take an umbrella and go out anyway,
which was good, but I think I might’ve thrown away my shoes
And it’s not like I’ve got the courage to go barefoot, so...
I guess I don’t really care? What do I want to do?
What should I do for dinner?
If the rain lets up, I’ll go out
Even though I don’t really want to see people
At this speed I swim through today,
And if my hand finally touches you…
Come on, try and open your eyes
Because I remember you and your sleepy eyes, even though I’ve forgotten them
There you are by the hill, laughing,
“It’s been so long, hasn’t it?”
as you bring your face close to mine
“Let’s go together,” you say
Under a barn in Lappland
On the old streets of Gamla Stan
The summer grass is getting in my way
At this speed I swim through today,
And if my hand finally touches you…
Come on, open your eyes
And see that I’ve forgotten you
Lift your head at the speed of the farewell
Someday dawn will finally break
Come on, open your eyes
And see that I’ve drawn pictures of your sleepy eyes so many times
Poetry
Revolving Lantern
A song resounds within my head
There’s a melody ringing out
My chest is in pain, I’m struggling, unable to breathe
Beyond 0 meters above sea level, my blurred vision wavers
The light shining through the crevices of the pier
sparkles like moonlight hitting the water’s surface
I’m at the bottom of a deep sea
I understand now,
The light that I’d always been seeing
the scenery,
my memories,
the rainy café terrace,
the night-imitating twilight,
Fujimidoori,
my journey to find the closest place to heaven,
the melodies,
the music,
this moment in time that feels like I’m having a long dream,
the scenery of that day,
all of it,
What I’m looking upon - it’s a revolving lantern
｢That’s Why I Gave Up On Music｣
♪～Dakara Boku wa Ongaku wo Yameta
That’s Why I Gave Up On Music
I’ve thought about it, but I still don’t understand
Under the blue sky, I waited for you
On that breezy afternoon, my imagination escaped the confines of the day
Hey, where do I go from here?
No one has told me how to proceed
I looked into your eyes and without a word I walked away
I’ve thought about it, but I still don’t understand
Youth is so boring
I tried to give up piano, but I can’t break the habit of playing on my desk
Hey, what will I do in the future?
It shouldn’t be music, right?
Don’t worry
Even if I drew a single line in my heart
No matter what I did, it wouldn’t disappear, even now, so
Hey, I still remember
I’m mistaken
I don’t understand, I don’t care
About all you humans or the truth or love or the world or pain or life
Wanting to know what’s right or wrong is just a self-preservation instinct
It’s your fault that I thought that
I’ve thought about it, but I still don’t understand why I truly don’t want to get older
Just thinking “Someday I’m going to die” makes my chest feel hollow
“What will I do in the future?”
When I grew up I understood
That I’m not going to do anything at all
How do I explain why I hate people who put on happy faces?
It’s an inferiority complex haunting my unsatisfied mind like a ghost
I’m not mistaken
Hey, with all your differences, you all are human
When you don’t have love or salvation or kindness or a foundation, it feels bad
Feeling pain at something like a love song is a self-preservation instinct
Do I really not care? It’s your fault
I’ve thought about it, but I still don’t understand
Why just living is painful
Why you can’t make a living from something like music
I don’t care if the lyrics or whatever are lazily done
I don’t care about anything
I’m probably not mistaken
I’m sure I’m not mistaken
I’m mistaken, I understand
I don’t care
About all you humans or the truth or love or salvation or kindness or life
Not being able to give the right answer is a self-preservation instinct
I don’t care, it’s your fault
Even I had faith in something once
Now the feeling is nothing but garbage
I wrote to you so many times
I didn’t care about whether I’d be rich and famous
It’s true, it’s really true, that’s how it was back then
That’s why I-
That’s why I gave up on music
Poetry
Reincarnation
After all this time, I still think about it.
Even in the end, I was selfish.
Even in the end, I can only think of music.
Elma, the letters and poems that I've written while on this trip...
I wonder if they'll reach you properly.
I wonder what you'll think when you see them.
I wonder if you'll understand what I mean.
I don't think you would understand.
After all this time.
After all this time, I still miss you.
I need to get there as fast as I can.
I wanted to see that crying face one more time.
I have to go.
I have to get there as fast as I can.
Even if I were to be reborn, I have to see you.
Even if I were to be reborn.
Even if I have to be reborn.
The thing that I just saw...
The sounds that I heard, they must be from the revolving lantern...
The revolving lantern's waves as gentle as the moonlight...
I closed my eyes.
I see something at the end of the road.
In front of the hill... Who's standing there?
I can picture your face.
I start to walk slowly.
It smells deeply of summer.
Behind my eyelids, I see the light.
A light similar to the dawn that illuminates only at night.
A soft, dazzling, pale light that unmistakably is;
the moonlight.
To Elma