A strange dance...
A strange...
dance...
I guess...
I recall the image of a bird
spreading its wings.
The bird looks at its reflection
in a puddle.
Wet with water, its feathers
gleam faintly.
Perhaps it flew through trees
laden with morning dew.
Even before the sun had fully risen,
its rays shone upon the bird's wings,
making them glisten so beautifully.
The bird in the puddle shakes its body,
and I can clearly see every drop
that is shaken off.
That's right. It's so crystal clear.
Many such sights exist in my mind.
I could say that I paint pictures
to download what's in my head.
There's a strange reality
in the panoramas of my mind.
And the resulting pictures
are just landscapes, so to speak.
Up until now, they haven't sold so well.
It was sunny outside.
I grabbed an empty paint tube
from the desk
and threw it in the bin,
dust scattering.
Caught in the spring sunlight
streaming through the window,
the particles sparkled,
as they swirled and danced.
Despite the beautiful weather,
my mood is dark.
Over the past few weeks, I've struggled
to paint anything meaningful.
It's not that I can't.
I just don't have the motivation.
I find myself alternating between
my bed and the canvas.
It's frustrating.
Birds.
(Bird chirping)
I envy birds.
They always seem to be having fun,
and have a reason to live
without even working.
See.
(Sound of bird song and flapping wings)
It's time to play that piece.
♪～(Piano Sonata 」Moonlight」)
(Cat meowing)
」Moon and Cat Dance」
♪～(Piano Sonata 」Moonlight」)
｢Bremen｣
♪～
♪Hey, you don't have to rack your brains out
♪'Cause you see, we can't get each other with just words
♪For now, let's lose ourselves in this sound
♪'Cause I don't ever want to forget this
♪My body is achromatic, feeling laidback
♪I'm getting on the groove with just the sound of the surging rainfall
♪Hey, let's live together and forever
♪At the corner of this night
♪～
♪"Hey, you see, it's okay to be the nobody that we are"
♪Weren't you the one who enticed me with these words?
♪A life with nothing but logics is so vapid
♪Do you still think that this is a waste of time?
♪Stuffing in a vacuum pack the scenery we see as we're parading around,
♪Grooving with the sound we make as we walk and stomp the ground,
♪It's just like we’re the town musicians of Bremen–
♪We have the march all to ourselves
♪Well then, breathe in and out quickly, and–
♪Let's sing like there's no tomorrow!
♪Shall we laugh? Do you wanna join me?
♪See, I'm singing a love song here,
♪ahahaha
♪Look, let's just take it easy, put all your worries behind!
♪See, there's nothing in this world worth killing yourself over
♪What shall I do tomorrow?
♪If you're free, let's get to know each other, alright?
♪～
♪Hey, you don't have to rack your brains out
♪The cells in your body have started dancing around,
♪So let's lose ourselves in this sound for now
♪But well, you don't have to if you can't
♪Going backpacking, trekking through the scenery inside our memories,
♪Getting into the groove, accompanied by the howling wind in spring
♪Let's sing together more
♪If you're free, let's fall in love
♪Well then, breath in, let your voice out, and–
♪Go ahead and sing like there's no tomorrow!
♪People are going to laugh at you anyway
♪'Cause everything's all messed up. Don't you agree?
♪Ahahaha
♪Look, let's just take it easy, let go of everything!
♪Playing the clown isn't exactly easy either, y'know
♪This chorus reads almost the same as the first, so you can just skip the next one
♪～
♪Well then, breathe in and out quickly–
♪Hey, just for today, can you please lend me your heart?
♪Let's sing like there's no tomorrow! Huh? What's wrong?
♪Are you guys making fun of me? Don't pretend you can't hear me
♪Look, let's just take it easy, put all your worries behind!
♪If your life's that unbearably miserable, just get away from it all
♪After a few years, nobody would even remember about it, I promise
♪Let's sing until we run out of breath!
♪Can you move? Do you wanna join me?
♪See, I'm singing a love song here,
♪ahahaha
♪Look, let's just take it easy, put all your worries behind!
♪See, there's nothing in this world worth killing yourself over
♪What shall I do tomorrow?
♪If you're free, let's laugh and smile together, alright?
♪While we're at it, let's get to understand each other, okay?
♪～
｢Rain with Cappuccino｣
♪My words that had faded to grey
♪are now a color like cappuccino
♪Enough of the excuses, leave them by the window
♪There are too many to count
♪～
♪My heart that had faded to grey
♪is now a color like cappuccino
♪Enough of the excuses, I’ll gulp down cappuccino
♪And pretend to be an idiot
♪The rain flows as if indecisive
♪We drown in the flowers storming around us
♪So you won’t fade away, I keep this memory–
♪I hope, I hope,
♪I hope you don’t overflow
♪～
♪The beach awaits the waves; a red evening sun shines
♪They’re reflected in the window
♪Visby in August, the roar of the sea
♪I wait in vain for a single sea breeze
♪The white of the flowers that swam in the summer,
the evening rain
♪Drown in the flowing night
♪So no one will fade away, keep this flower–
♪I hope, I hope,
♪I hope you’ll stick it to the inside of your heart
♪～
♪Things have been strange for a long time
♪I just want someone to tell me one way to live
♪I have no way to pay for it anymore
♪But if it’s too hard to answer, a single word would be enough
♪I don’t understand
♪I seriously don’t get it at all
♪The rain flows as if indecisive
♪We drown in the flowers storming around us
♪So you won’t fade away, I write this song–
♪I hope, I hope,
♪I hope you haven’t forgotten it even now
♪Another summer comes to an end,
♪and I hold a single flower in my heart,
♪Flowing beneath my eyelids
♪So you won’t fade away, I wrote this song
♪I hope,
♪I hope you don’t overflow
♪～
(Sigh)
Something is lacking in your paintings.
That's what she said that day.
My ex-girlfriend who broke up with me
and left this place.
She's a promoter who works mostly on
small exhibitions in the city.
According to her, she said,
」Your pictures look like photos.」
Not because they are drawn precisely.
But because they are like copies of
scenery that can be found anywhere.
They're just... not interesting.
Her eyes were right.
People aren't touched by pictures drawn
without any thought.
Truth is, I've been content
being an unsuccessful artist,
barely ever drawing pictures.
Night has come.
Ultimately, I was never inspired
and spent the day aimlessly.
Maybe I need a change of scenery.
(Wind)
When I open the window,
a warm breeze blows in.
The moonlight shines down
between the clouds.
It sneaks inside through the window
and dances off the piano keys like a fish.
There's a perfect song for this feeling.
It's a piano sonata
that even an amateur like me can play.
♪～(Piano Sonata 」Moonlight」)
(Bird chirping)
(Wings fluttering)
A bird.
Hey.
Go on.
What's wrong. Go.
It was a small canary.
It stares at me with tiny,
black, beady eyes.
Its beak is round and pointed,
like a peanut.
It stands, its feet sticking out of its yellow
feathers, grasping the window sill.
Go on.
Oh well. Whatever. A tiny spectator.
Ah...
I always sit at the piano the same way.
I put my hands on the keys.
I check the position of the notes.
I place my foot on the pedals.
I sit up straight and raise my face.
Then I tense my arms.
♪～(Piano Sonata 」Moonlight」)
(Wings fluttering)
(Clears throat)
♪～(Piano Sonata 」Moonlight」)
(Wings fluttering)
The canary spreads its wings.
♪～(Piano Sonata 」Moonlight」)
It opens them slowly,
goes off balance, then closes them.
♪～(Piano Sonata 」Moonlight」)
I try playing a single long note.
(Piano plays)
(Sound of flapping wings)
It spreads its wings wide.
This time, I play a note, short and quick.
(Piano plays)
(Wings fluttering)
It flaps its wings then quickly stops.
I blink my eyes.
Have I finally lost my mind?
The canary stares at me
with its beady, black eyes.
♪～(Piano Sonata 」Moonlight」)
The canary spreads its yellow wings wide.
With the moonlight shining on it,
it glows faintly.
It flutters its wings,
as if it is dancing a waltz
to my poor piano playing.
Hah...
I smile without thinking.
On a whim,
I grab the sketchbook
and pencil from the music stand.
The canary stands there without moving.
I think, 」This is the first time
I've drawn a living canary.」
The night draws on.
Even the next day,
I sit before the canvas
scratching my head.
As always,
I don't feel as if I can draw a thing.
But I think I drew
an interesting sketch yesterday.
Well, it's just a drawing of a canary.
I don't think I can use it for anything.
I stand up and stretch.
Then, I thought about
the canary who flew off
somewhere after last night.
I open the window and look
at the sea far away.
(Sound of the sea breeze)
The sea breeze is blowing.
I imagine the yellow wings that have flown
(Sound of the sea breeze)
so very far away.
｢Goodbye Molten｣
♪～
♪With my borrowed book held in my hand,
♪I make my way down the footpath along the river
♪Only two pages ’till I’m done reading
♪I don’t wanna know what happens next
♪～
♪It’s about a boy who goes on a journey
♪Heading endlessly north on the back of a bird,
♪His trusty pal is a goose named Morten —
♪That’s the kind of story I’m reading
♪Goodbye, Morten
♪We’ve always been trying to soar
♪With arms wide open, bounding towards the sky
♪Even though there’s never been a chance we’ll get off the ground
♪Goodbye, Morten
♪You laugh even as we tumble down
♪I catch the scent of the earth beneath us
♪and feel a knot build deep in my chest
♪Summer has arrived
♪～
♪Clutching onto my sadness like it’s its own fortune
♪I make my way down the path right before the summer comes
♪Only two pages ’till I’m done reading
♪I don’t wanna know what happens next yet
♪Chasing after your ever-slightly taller figure,
♪I dash up the usual hill
♪Like geese flying through the sky,
♪We open up our arms
♪Goodbye Morten
♪We try to soar, even still
♪We just don’t wanna know the truth
that we’re not as special as we think
♪Goodbye, Morten
♪You laugh even as we tumble down
♪When I see your face,
♪it’s like you have no clue we’re growing older
♪Summer has arrived
♪～
♪Once again, you’re growing taller
♪Before I knew it, you became distant
♪Little by little, we drifted apart
♪Like a twig splitting in two
♪With my faded book clutched in my hand,
♪I make my way down that old familiar path
♪Just a few hundred steps ’till the top of that hill
♪There’s someone standing there
♪Goodbye, Morten
♪You’re still trying to soar, even now
♪With your eyes glimmering,
♪it’s like nothing has changed from back then
♪Goodbye, Morten
♪I get the sense that we’ve always held the fact
we can’t fly close to our hearts,
♪and feel a knot build deep in my chest
♪You’re watching me,
♪but your smile never fades, not even for a second
♪Summer has arrived
♪～
♪With my faded book clutched in my hand,
♪I make my way down the footpath along the river
♪Only one page left ’till I’m done reading
♪I flip over the last sheet
♪Goodbye, Morten
｢Matasaburo｣
♪～
♪When you step into a pool of water,
♪You let out a big yawn
♪I want you to summon a storm so fierce
♪That will blow away even this sky
♪I was waiting for the wind
♪Because I'm sure an empty life would be too boring
♪If the summer wind blows through the fresh leaves,
♪Just blow the words away as well
♪Until nobody can utter a single word,
♪Just go and swallow us whole
♪Doddo-do, dodoh-do
♪～
♪"So you do really summon the wind, huh?!"
♪I said, as I stared wide-eyed in amazement
♪And so, bluntly, you said
♪"Heh, I can freely bend it to my will"
♪I was waiting for the wind
♪Because a society that fits the mold is too suffocating
♪"Then I'll summon a rain even heavier!
♪Along with some wind that would also blow away this shared sentiment"
♪If the summer wind blows through the fresh leaves,
♪Just cast everything away
♪If we stay this way,
♪Soon we will even forget who we are
♪Blow away the green walnuts as well
♪Blow away the sour quince as well
♪Make the wind that will destroy this town
♪Rage even fiercer, as fierce as it can be
♪Come forth, summer wind; blow through the fresh leaves
♪And cast everything away
♪Go and blow away the sadness, dreams, and everything else
♪Matasaburo
♪If we head towards the long road,
♪The words are your wind
♪Until nobody can utter a single word,
♪Just go and swallow us whole
♪Doddo-do, dodoh-do
♪～
A single deer stares at me.
I stand beneath a tree with red blossoms.
I am holding a small box.
I realize that this is a dream.
(Sigh)
I think it's like my girlfriend
once said long ago.
My pictures are not interesting.
They lack any kind of appeal.
In creative work,
the message alone isn't everything.
If you want a picture to sell,
it needs to tell a story.
Unless your picture
has something that says, 」Look at me,」
it will never touch other people's hearts.
As a child, I was better at art
than with people.
Come to think of it, I still want to draw
what I wanted to then.
I have a very clear picture
of a scene in my mind.
Whenever I want to draw,
that comes to mind first.
A road where sunlight shines
between the trees.
A shopping arcade at sunset.
A bench and a church.
A town in a foreign country.
Rain on a cafe terrace.
It's so clear, it's annoying.
I can even see clearly each leaf
in an unfamiliar landscape.
I output it onto the canvas
without making a single change to it.
My drawings are not interesting.
(Sigh)
Another day has ended.
I light a cigarette
and place my hands on
the window sill as I exhale.
Then I feel something slimy
on my fingertips.
Yuck.
I see something light green.
(Frog croaking)
It's a frog.
I don't like these kinds of things.
Hey. Go away. Get out.
Don't make me say,
」Leap frog out of here.」
Hurry up. Get out.
I have a strange sense of
déjà vu as I shoo it away.
I feel as if I did
something similar before.
Oh well. Whatever.
Whoa!
(Frog croaking)
The thing came inside.
Give me a break, would you?
Hey, this isn't your home, you know.
Go on. Get out.
(Clicks tongue)
I finally realize why I feel this déjà vu.
It's that canary that showed up one day.
This thing has
that same strange impudence.
I give up and drop my arms,
striking the piano keys.
(Piano sound)
The frog twitches.
I tentatively raise my index finger
and press a key again.
It's a G note.
(Piano plays)
The frog slowly lifts its body.
I play the key again, and the frog moves.
I pull out the chair and sit down again.
Then I play the melody from 」Moonlight.」
♪～(Piano Sonata 」Moonlight」)
With its body still lifted,
it raises its arms.
On a whim,
I grab the sketchbook and pencil again.
I sketch the figure of the still frog
with its head held high
with my pen.
Though it's an ordinary frog,
it's almost as if
it has a mysterious allure to it.
I draw, and then I play the piano again.
I draw and play, play and draw.
It's figure is now in my sketchbook.
The frog's arms slowly wander in the air,
as if it is looking for something.
I can smell the night sea breeze.
The frog lifts its nose high
and flaps it little green arms.
It looked as if it was dancing
a strange dance.
｢Howl At The Moon｣
♪～
♪I'm howling at the moon by the roadside
♪I walk through the town,
♪Not even noticing that the moon is waxing
♪Without anyone noticing, the night swiftly sinks into the deep
♪When I come to my senses,
I notice that people around me are standing still
♪They're looking at my face
♪"Quit acting like you know me!"
♪I bark at them, pretending to be a beast
♪I want to toss every single thing away
♪Please, tell me that I'm alive
♪If you sing like you're howling at the moon, ah,
♪things will become vivid and beautiful
♪I want to try satisfying myself with this malice
♪by smashing open the earth with an icepick
♪If you sing like you're howling at the moon,
♪Ah, things will be as you want it to be
♪～
♪There's a blueish-white moon by the roadside
♪But people are saying "Where is it?"
♪Can't anyone see it?
♪What a bunch of unsightly beasts
♪I point my finger there and people start to turn around
♪They're moving while staying faceless as they are
♪Something is watching me
♪From the shadows of the wharf over there
♪I don't have any faith in you, not in the slightest
♪Nobody is expecting anything out of you
♪If you sing like you're howling at the moon, ah,
♪things will become vivid and beautiful
♪I want to dip the tip of a solid pen
in a moonlit lake and try drawing a line on the waves
♪If you sing like you're howling at the moon, ah,
♪things will become gorgeous
♪And time will flow according to its whims
♪～
♪Everyone thinks that I'm some pitiful, ill person!
♪I want to toss every single thing away
♪I- I haven't violated the world enough, not yet
♪If you sing like you're howling at the moon,
♪ah, things will become beautiful
♪Please, smash my skull open with an icepick
♪and fill it up with some lukewarm soup
♪"Sing like you're howling at the moon!"
♪Ah, I say to the beast residing in the depths of my windpipe
♪This world is at the mercy of your heart's desire
♪～
♪I'm howling at the moon by the roadside
｢451｣
♪～
♪I was looking at that sun
♪burning intensely
♪When I did, someplace in my chest started to burn a little
♪Someone passing by the road raised their voice,
♪"Look! What a peculiar man," and as they said, laughing—
♪—the paper I had touched with the ends of my fingers
finally caught a flame
♪Hurry and set it alight! Burn it down!
♪Burn it down!
♪Rejoice in this rapture, and—
♪Come now, let's sublimate this sensation:
♪Dance!
♪～
♪Look, I can see the faces of the men gathered
♪They're trying to figure out the intent behind the fire
♪Look, what peculiar people!
♪And raising my voice so loud,
♪I'm losing my head on a single blaze
♪Hurry up and burn! In the echoing midst of the voices in protest
♪O Bundle of Paper, bloom with red!
♪Aah, what a pain—
♪hurry and burn it down!
♪Burn it down! Burn it down!
♪Let's rejoice in this sorrow and
♪Hurry to arson it down to the ground, then
♪dance!
♪Dance!
♪～
♪Touch, extinguish, touch, extinguish
♪Touch me and open the door to my chest
♪Burn it fast and show me the ashes...
♪And to the sooty soul sitting in the deepest recesses there—
♪—hurry and set it alight! Burn it down!
♪Burn it down!
♪Love it so much you become jealous!
♪Hurry and arson it to the ground, then burn it down!
♪Burn it down!
♪Love until you've grown tired, then
♪Hurry and consume, then
♪dance!
♪Dance!
♪～
♪Now create, then
♪burn it down!
♪Burn it down!
(Phone ringing)
」That's like Kenji Miyazawa,」
my girlfriend says on the phone.
Isn't Kenji Miyazawa that author
from long ago in our textbooks?
」Yes. Haven't you read Gauche the Cellist?
Gauche is visited nightly
by an animal who asks him
to play his cello.」
Really?
」This is what that's like.
A serious guy like you
would never make that up,」
she adds with a laugh.
I murmur that it's no lie.
Gauche the Cellist...
Come to think of it,
I think I read it as a child.
It is similar. But it's also not.
The ones that visit me dance.
At night,
they come to my window and stare.
And they only react when I play the piano.
The frog raised and waved its arms,
and the canary spread its wings.
」Really?」
I thought she didn't believe me.
I guess that only makes sense.
Not long ago, a bat came to visit me.
(Bat cries)
It's not often you see a bat close-up.
So it was interesting.
(Bat cries)
It stood up straight on the window sill.
We think of bats being upside down.
(Bat cries)
But when it isn't upside down, it's more...
I guess you'd call it handsome.
It gave me the impression
that it was a gentleman.
」Really?」
There's more. Yesterday,
a rabbit was outside my window.
(Sound of a rabbit hopping)
I was suspicious, but when I played
the piano, it lifted its front legs
(Sound of a rabbit hopping)
and stretched out its arms,
swinging them back and forth.
(Sound of a rabbit hopping)
」That's cute.」
That was the fourth animal.
These aren't coincidences.
It made me wonder what it exactly was
these animals who came at night
were here to do.
When they moved their bodies
to the rhythm of the piano,
it was like they were trying to
express something.
That's it. This was a dance.
The spirit of a long-dead
regret-filled musician
is possessing the animals
and making them dance!
Might that be it?
」Well, even if I do believe your story,
were those really dances?
Maybe you just imagined they were dancing?」
You're wrong.
You won't understand unless you see.
」Really? Then maybe
I'll come over to watch sometime.」
I was a little shocked
and at a loss for words.
I'm not sure that's a good idea.
They don't come that often.
They hardly ever visit me.
」I'm just kidding,」 she said.
I realized she must believe
I'm lying even more now.
Anyway, that's what's been up.
I have no ideas, so I sketch them
to distract myself.
」I like it. The pictures
would go well with the story.
You should do children's books.」
You think? All I can do is draw.
」Drawings are all you need.」
Who would enjoy that?
」What? Nowadays, there are
many books of just pictures to imagine to.
What's more, a picture can say
just as much as words can.」
I'm impressed by what she says.
Who said that?
」You did.
Have you forgotten what you once told me?
You sure have changed,」
she says, poking fun at me.
I couldn't respond.
She was right.
A picture can say just as much as words.
All creations are nothing more
than words in a different form.
I was once so passionate
that I spoke words like that.
I had a passion that expresses more
than just skill and practice can.
Did I really say that?
I felt a little embarrassed
when saying that.
Then I hated myself
for feeling embarrassed.
I thought to myself, 」I think I understand
why she lost interest in me.」
I change the subject.
About that story, what happens at the end?
」Huh? You mean Gauche?」
Yeah.
She took a meaningful tone and said,
」He pondered about
the animals who visited,
wishing that he had treated them better.」
Really?
」Maybe you should be more careful.
Like they say, hindsight is 20/20.」
I realized she was being ironic.
Are you referring to us who broke up
because things didn't work out?
Well, anyway, I'll be careful.
I heard her laughing over the phone.
In the now silent room,
I pondered the words she said
just before hanging up the phone.
」Why not try drawing something
based on those animals?」
As I look at the sketches before me,
I imagine them standing there in my home.
♪Like flowers bloom, a touch of red on your cheeks.
｢Miyakoochi｣
♪Flowers bloom on your rosy cheeks
♪Wavelets rolling make a sea
♪On the water’s edge, you alone only smile
♪Now, in a memory I leave the capital
♪～
♪The humming sounds nice, doesn’t it?
♪I’m leaving tomorrow
♪The black-tailed gulls cried out, didn’t they
♪And even the other birds are crying
♪After we’re dried somewhat, it’ll be time to go
♪Tossed around by the summer wind,
you cast a pale shadow
♪Smoothly do flowers bloom on your rosy cheeks
♪These wavelets roll into the sea of the night
♪On the water’s edge, you alone only wave your hand
♪Now, in a memory I leave the capital
♪～
♪The sunrise looks pretty, doesn’t it?
♪The boat’s already set out now
♪The black-tailed gulls cried out, didn’t they
♪Even you’re crying
♪Since I drifted away from humanity,
all that roars are waves crashing towards me
♪A soaring bird flies on far away,
from tomorrow to far beyond
♪Falling into the water, getting swept away,
finally brings some misery
♪The sea is a boat that longs for you
♪The regret these fingers write are all they have
♪Are these scattering memories waves leaving the capital?
♪～
♪This boat that’s left the capital goes on
♪Water and time alike flow along
♪I will stay in your memories
♪Simply as a memory
♪～
♪This love’s the seafoam that ebbs and flows
♪From your rosy cheeks
♪On the water’s edge, you alone only smile
♪Now, in a memory I’ll—
♪Smoothly do flowers bloom on your rosy cheeks
♪These wavelets roll into the sea of the night
♪On the water’s edge, you alone only wave your hand
♪Now, farewell, for I’ll leave the capital
♪～
♪The moon that floated in the night
｢Cloudless｣
♪like a jellyfish has split open
♪When I glance at the back of the bus stop
♪You, as you were that summer, are in my head
♪～
♪Only
♪Torii gates, dried-out clouds;
♪the scent of summer strokes my cheek
♪Until I become an adult, look,
♪I’ll keep standing on tiptoe to make myself taller
♪Tired out from playing,
behind the bus stop I’ll even look at the sky
♪Even if the summer comes to an end soon
♪I’ll definitely, definitely remember
♪Becoming an adult without being able to catch up
♪Night blooms in your pocket
♪If I can’t put it into words I’ll be alone
♪But that’s all right, I’ve already resigned myself to it
♪Only
♪～
♪A summer day, dried-out clouds,
♪Nanking cherry trees, a rusted stoplight
♪In my memories, it always smells like summer
♪Photographs are just scraps of paper
♪And memories are nothing but garbage
♪Because I didn’t understand that,
♪I kept my mouth shut
♪In my memory, you rest forever
♪on the single stone in a summer field
♪Becoming an adult while looking down
♪I can’t catch up, it’s just a sunny day for you
♪Unable to put things into words, we climbed the hill
♪In our shadows, night is blooming
♪～
♪We’ve become adults while looking down
♪Clap your hands how you like
♪Climbing the road up the hill at sunset
♪Our shadows…
♪Becoming an adult without being able to catch up
♪Night blooms in your pocket
♪Even if we can’t put it into words, we are one
♪That’s enough, I think
♪I’m only chewing over memories of you
♪～
♪Only
｢Chinokate｣
♪～
♪The glass that swallowed the sunset
♪Looks like a ruby
♪The half-drank essence of my saturday life
♪I left on the table
♪The white flower in the vase
♪Seems to have withered because it was too kind
♪It was truly precious
♪But I guess it's time to replace it…
♪Ah, the sunset.
♪Looks really beautiful, don't you think?
♪Is there really no map that shows
♪the details of our long, distant journey ahead?
♪I'm not sure if we wouldn't get lost
♪Well, that's fine.
♪It's fine that way, so…
♪Let's throw away all the things that we actually didn't need,
♪and the sofa and book too
♪And make our way to the town
♪～
♪Actually, our heart resides inside our head
♪The things we did wrong
♪have now been laid down in letters
♪The white flower in the vase
♪Seems like it has withered a while ago
♪If it truly was precious,
♪I guess I shouldn't have bought it in the first place…
♪Ah, the petals fell.
♪Nevertheless, it's still beautiful, don't you agree?
♪Don't you feel that the dream that
♪you've always wanted to fulfill is tying you down?
♪If I have just the tiniest speck of courage
to say that you can give it up…
♪Let's throw away the bag, pen,
and even the things you really wanted to have
♪And make our way to the town
♪～
♪You threw away the "self"
♪That you wanted to be
♪It was truly precious
♪And yet I only start to remember about it now,
all too late
♪I didn't even realize
♪That the white flower in the vase has withered
♪Even though the truly precious one
♪Was the person who replaces the flower
♪Ah, wait.
♪You're really leaving, aren't you…
♪Is there really no map that shows
♪the details of our long, distant journey ahead?
♪I'm not sure if we wouldn't get lost
♪Well, that's fine.
♪It's fine that way, so…
♪Let's throw away all the things that we actually didn't need,
♪and the sofa and book too
♪Really, it's fine
♪Would there be a dazzling ray of light
that will keep illuminating your night?
♪Would you leave no matter what?
♪Well, that's fine.
♪It's fine that way, so…
♪After you've finished reading everything,
♪please open your eyes
♪Then, let's throw away this book
and make our way to the town
♪～
(Sound of insect wings)
I hear wings.
Something flies in through
the open window.
(Sound of insect wings)
It's a flying insect.
Perhaps a kind of stag beetle.
It has two short pincers.
♪～(Piano Sonata 」Moonlight」)
I rush to get my sketchbook.
One night, I see a chameleon.
As I play the piano,
I watch its tail hanging from
(The sound of a chameleon tail
tapping the piano top)
the piano top as it swings
in time with the rhythm.
(The sound of a chameleon tail
tapping the piano top)
Sometimes,
the tip of its curled tail extends,
(The sound of a chameleon tail
tapping the piano top)
and its shadow traces
the black keys of the piano,
swaying back and forth
like the surface of waves.
I'm used to it now.
I don't care what comes anymore.
(Tapping on window)
One night, I hear
the sound of tapping on the window.
It was a beautiful night
with a waning moon.
I listen closely.
There is also a strange sound,
like of a poorly fitted door closing.
(Sound of something creaking)
It's a deer.
A stag is sitting there.
It's a stag with horns
and a beautiful coat.
It's lying curled up
just outside the window,
lifting its head and looking at me.
I catch a whiff of what I once smelled
in a cowshed on a farm.
(Tapping on the window)
No way. This time it's impossible.
(Tapping on window)
Oh, give me a break.
I can hear the deer's breathing.
(Sigh)
I finally give up,
and back away toward the piano.
I play a single note
and hear that creaking door sound.
(Sound of something creaking)
There's no doubt.
That is the sound it makes.
As if trying to escape reality,
I am impressed by the sound it makes.
I begin playing the introduction,
which I have played often.
♪～(Piano Sonata 」Moonlight」)
(Deer's moan)
Please, try to be silent.
Try not to moan.
(Tapping on window)
None of that either.
The deer watches me
with a gaze
that's as black as the deep night,
a mysterious color that draws you in.
♪～(Piano Sonata 」Moonlight」)
The deer closes its eyes.
Then it opens and closes
its mouth again and again.
It raises its head
and stretches its nose
as if to approach the window.
Occasionally, its red tongue peeks out.
I can hear the deer's breathing.
For some reason,
the sound has a nostalgic feel.
After finishing the introduction,
I start playing 」Moonlight」 again.
The deer lowers its head back down,
opens its eyes, and looks at me.
This is the only part I can play.
The deer looks at me.
It's as if he's saying, 」That's fine.」
I start playing 」Moonlight」 again.
I play only the introduction,
as if going round and round
in the same place.
(Waves)
(Sound of a toy piano)
(Owl hooting)
I found this on the beach.
Some one must have tossed it out.
It made me wonder
if it would dance
if it wasn't played on my piano.
I see feathers sticking out of the pot.
I bet I'm the only human
who's ever carried an owl in a pot.
It's dark black eyes look at me.
There are yellow circles like egg yolks
covering those black eyes,
like crescent moons.
I open my sketchbook
and start drawing with my pencil.
The owl in the pot stands there
with a puzzled look.
Long ago, I often used to dream of
becoming a bird.
Oh. Not a bird like you.
A bird that spreads its wings wide.
Its wings shining faintly with the dew
that wet its wings
as it flew between the trees.
The sunlight before it has fully risen is
almost annoyingly beautiful.
My body shivers.
Then, I fly
toward the sun.
Eventually, I run out of energy and fall.
When I woke up, I remembered it clearly.
When I drew it on paper,
I got a mysteriously good feeling.
Now that I think about it,
that was the first picture I drew.
(Sound of a toy piano)
I doubt I am any different than then.
Or rather, I have not changed.
I am better at using a brush and pen,
but that is all.
Only my sketching is better.
Only my perspective is more accurate.
Only my lines are more beautiful.
What is in my head, what is before me,
I am merely copying what I see there.
When asked if that's what I want to draw,
I tilt my head.
I am empty.
I sometimes become afraid.
Is what I am doing actually
not much different than
what a camera does?
(Sound of a toy piano)
When I think too much about things
like that, I play this song.
Piano sonata 14, the Moonlight Sonata.
I love this song.
I was taught it when I was a child.
It clearly sounds like a depressing song,
but how can I put this...
Nobody has ever agreed with me on this,
but when I play this, I become incredibly
nostalgic.
My eyes meet the yellow crescent moons.
I don't care and keep playing the keys.
Every time the scratchy sound is played,
I see the owl fluffing its wings
in discomfort.
｢The Fifth Night｣
♪～
｢Snow Country｣
♪Coming out of the long tunnel on the border,
we find the snow country
♪taking on the stillness of
a bone-chilly night to lay white.
♪～
♪Casting a sidelong glance
at the snowy old townscape,
♪the snow county is just imbued with the memory
of the springtime with you.
♪My hesitation covers the moon
and it's dark like the bottom of the sea.
♪Sitting in a daze, we're looking at our own reflections
on the surface of the water.
♪～
♪Stretching over a dining table and a long bar,
the snow country is
♪just catching the scent of the stillness
of spring star flowers.
♪Your tears scatter in the wind and it's like
we're in the middle of the spring.
♪Sitting in a daze, we're looking at our own reflections
on the surface of the soup.
♪～
♪Our melancholy piles up day after day
and it looks like the snow country.
♪I beg you to hesitate. I hope you care too.
♪Until the snow melts.
♪Until the love is solved.
♪～
♪Coming out of the long tunnel on the border,
we found ourselves
♪taking on the stillness of a bone-chilly night
and tinged with white.
♪～
｢Whale｣
♪Your pectoral fins
♪swim by the window,
♪looking like melted
♪and softened amber.
♪The tip of your nose,
♪your dorsal fin and moustache,
♪and your quiet eyes look like
♪they belong to the night.
♪Talking, crying,
♪we were stroking the waves
♪as if feeling nostalgic for the land.
♪Drop your eyelids and cover your eyes.
♪Sleep tight so that you won't awake right away
♪with your breath spouting out.
♪Now swim deep, swim on
♪in the waves of your shallow sleep
♪falling into a white slumber.
♪Your chirping
♪and dappled sunlight on the sofa
♪remind me of the seashore
♪that swayed softly.
♪Laughing, weeping,
♪we are waiting for the waves
♪so that we can recall before long.
♪Travel through the waves and dive deep,
♪deeper and deeper until you suffocate
♪with your breath spouting out.
♪Now swim deep, swim on
♪with your long tail fin
♪laid down on the waves.
♪～
♪Talking, crying,
♪we were stroking the waves
♪hoping to see each other again someday.
♪Drop your eyelids and cover your eyes.
♪Sleep tight so that you won't awake from a dream
♪and forgive yourself already.
♪Now swim deep, swim on
♪in the waves of your shallow sleep
♪falling into a white slumber.
♪～
(Phone ringing)
Did you see the picture I sent?
What did you think?
Actually, I tried drawing
like you told me before.
When I used those animals
as a motif for my drawings,
it was unbelievably easy to draw them.
This series of pictures
is called 」Dancing Animals.」
I think
they've turned out really interesting.
Yeah.
Uh-huh.
Oh, uh...
Canary, rabbit, chameleon,
owl, leaf beetle, frog, bat,
and the deer.
Huh? No, seriously.
I was visited by a deer. A stag.
Yeah, I get it. It sounds unbelievable.
Yes, the first one is of a human...
I mean, humans are animals too,
so I just had to draw it.
The motif?
Uh, well...
Yeah?
Huh? An exhibition?
Where?
Oh, there.
Are you sure? I mean...
Wait. I'll do it.
This is a great chance. Sure.
This makes me so happy. Thank you.
I'll prep what I've drawn before
so they can be displayed too.
Sure. Let's meet so we can
talk things over face-to-face.
Okay. See you later.
This is a golden opportunity.
All right.
Let's do this!
｢Setting Sun｣
♪Cheeks softly colored by the deep red of the sun
♪We shut our eyes in the sunset that burst forth
♪～
♪I couldn’t help but be sad
♪My hands got wet in the sun
♪Besides, it can’t be helped that it’s radiant
♪Returning home at a loss for words
♪Because the red
♪is glowing as if it were falling,
♪Just a little longer
♪Even if I was able to just love myself a little more
♪When I notice the setting sun,
I can’t keep my eyes open
♪In the quiet evening calm
♪I couldn’t help being sad
♪I touched the sun
♪It seems to burn weakly
♪It barely charred my fingertips
♪The grapes seemed to have grown too high
♪For me to reach, so I stopped trying
♪I wonder if I’ve fallen in love
♪Just like the sun,
♪I’m falling even though there’s no reason to yet.
♪(I'd rather—)
♪～
♪Cheeks softly colored by the deep red of the sun
♪If the sunset bursting across the sky just illuminates our path
♪In a little while, I will be able to love myself
♪I saw that shy you in the setting sun
♪In the quiet evening calm
♪As we closed our eyes
｢Fireworks of Shoes｣
♪～
♪Look, look,
♪I don’t have the words to say anything
♪Because, because I’ve been left open-mouthed
♪(So—)
♪～
♪Look, look,
♪Even if I stay silent, words aren’t necessary
♪Because my eyes will speak for me
♪Forgetting is a fruit that bugs have begun to eat
♪All that remains in my memory is an always-smiling face
♪As I’m flying through the twilight-colored sky,
♪Even shooting through the atmosphere,
♪Below me, rapidly growing small,
♪Is the town where you were
♪Beneath my shoes, flowers bloomed
♪Giant flowers of fire bloomed
♪“I’ll leave behind everything that’s in my heart,”
I think
♪That’s the kind of summer I could see
♪～
♪Look, look,
♪Even if I try to get to know you, it’s ambiguous
♪Because you’re full of pride
♪There’s nothing that can make me feel refreshed
♪But the sky is beautiful again today
♪I’m sure that everything I’ve eaten is a compensation paid to life
♪I’m too late, and now I can’t even become a nighthawk
♪Dancing in the dawn-colored sky
♪“What do you wish for?” is such a foolish question
♪I grew up and forgot about it
♪That you’re reflected in my eyes is such a nuisance
♪Flowers were always ringing out beneath me
♪Giant flowers of fire were ringing out
♪“The noise alone makes me cry,”
I think
♪That’s the kind of summer I heard
♪～
♪Look, look,
♪Even if I fly in the sky, there’s no end to it
♪Because I’ll surely end up searching for you
♪(So—)
♪As I’m flying in the twilight-colored sky,
♪Breaking free of even the present of this planet,
♪Below me, rapidly growing small
♪And then disappearing, is the town where you were
♪In the summer sky, flowers bloomed
♪Giant flowers of fire bloomed
♪“I want to keep crying forever,”
I think
♪That’s the kind of summer that vanished
♪～
Okay. I see.
Yes. I'll be careful.
Thank you always.
The exhibition? It's coming soon.
As a sign of gratitude, as my landlord,
can I invite you?
Oh, I see. Ha ha ha...
No, it's okay.
Yes. Okay.
Goodbye.
It's not easy living in this day and age.
Seems like I haven't painted for days.
Probably because I've been busy prepping.
(Cat meowing)
I hear a cat meowing somewhere.
I open the window and look outside.
Nothing there.
Oh well, whatever.
I leave the window open
and sit at the piano.
I touch the keys.
I begin playing the intro
to 」Moonlight.」
♪～(Piano Sonata 」Moonlight」)
After playing a while,
I hear something at the window.
A cat suddenly appears
and sits on the piano.
I watch the cat as I continue playing.
The cat raises its nose
into the air and stands up.
It closes its eyes,
as if listening to the notes.
I stop playing.
The cat stops moving.
It opens its eyes
and I see the tips of its hair moving.
I've been drawing pictures of you.
All of these here.
They're pretty fun, right?
I guess the landlord must have seen me.
He said he thought I'd been feeding
the animals.
When I told him the animals came
simply because I was playing the piano,
he looked at me as if I was mad.
So he told me he's taking back
the piano at the end of the month.
This belongs to the landlord.
His niece wants to learn,
so he's giving it to her.
Mind you, I'm sure there were
complaints about the noise, too.
This piano is going to disappear.
That means there's no reason
for you guys to keep coming.
I don't like it.
You're not disposable materials.
It's thanks to you, I made this art,
and I've been able to do
a solo exhibition.
I mean, you guys,
you come here to hear me play, right?
♪～(Piano Sonata 」Moonlight」)
The eyes of the cat sitting on
the piano meet mine.
I'm stunned.
The cats' eyes are
the color of the deep night.
They shimmer like the surface of water.
I feel as if I've seen this color before.
Sometime, long, long ago.
Somewhere.
What is this?
I felt something running down on my face.
(Sniffling)
Tears.
Overflowing tears.
The image of me
desperately wiping away my tears
can be seen in the mirror in the room.
The moonlight
gently illuminates the piano keys.
The cat quietly approaches me.
Then it puts its nose
against mine as if to kiss me.
The cat silently goes out the window.
This was the last time I ever saw them.
｢Left-Right Confusion｣
♪You're poking my cheeks with your right hand
♪While I'm holding a warm mug with my left hand
♪Your right eyebrow looks a little droopy
♪It's hard to believe how many mornings have arrived
♪I'm content with just one thing
♪Just one peony whose flowers never fall
♪A happiness that touches you,
♪And makes you forget even your heart
♪Really, I'm fine with just one thing
♪A night so dark and deep you can't tell left from right
♪The stillness of going on a journey alone
♪If I could convey to you even one of these things…
♪Your left eyebrow looks a little droopy
♪I just can't seem to remember
♪It feels like I just never knew
♪About the novel you bought one day that you had in your right hand
♪Wait, maybe it was in your left hand…?
♪～
♪I'm content with just one thing
♪Just one ray of sunshine that shines through the night
♪A sentimentality that would touch you
♪and open your heart and let me see through it
♪Really, I'm fine with just one thing
♪Like the fact that you can move forward
even during a fluttering summer hailstorm if you just feel your way through
♪Or that your eyes won't close
♪～
♪I would tear off my heart from my body, little by little,
♪And hand it to you.
♪I will give my everything to you, so…
♪I will give you the ruby from the hilt of my sword,
♪and the sapphires from my eyes
♪And I will put my heart of lead beside you
♪I'm content with just one thing
♪Just one peony whose flowers never falls
♪A happiness that touches you,
♪And makes you forget even your tears
♪I'm fine with just a little bit
♪A bit of the sun to stop today’s light rain
♪Just a little bit,
♪Let me leave just a little bit of my footprints in your world
♪Do you understand? That your happiness
♪Isn't confined to just one thing
♪A night so dark and deep you can't tell left from right
♪The long journey you will embark on from now on
♪The fact that I'm the only one that doesn’t smile
♪If I could convey to you even just one of them…
♪I can't taste anything no matter what I eat
♪It feels like I've lost my body
♪I believed
♪That your heart and mine would always be one
｢Spring Thief｣
♪～
♪When I crossed the elevated bridge,
I could see the blue sky peeking through the clouds
♪It's really hot lately,
so I was just waiting for a breeze
♪Sitting beneath the shade of a tree,
♪There's something stuck on my cheeks
♪When I look up, flowers are blooming and falling right above my head
♪Gently falling, we're now forgetting to even breathe
♪And it's too much work to even blink
♪Well, even today will turn into the past tomorrow
♪So I'm just waiting for the wind
♪That's why, we're now forgetting even our voices
♪And it's too much work to even say goodbye
♪Flowers are just falling beneath the sunny sky
♪Right now, a spring storm is happening
♪～
♪The next day, I met up with you again at the same place
♪There weren't that many people who went to see the cherry blossoms anymore
♪And I couldn't smell spring in the air anymore
♪I guess summer will come again this year
♪When I crossed the elevated bridge,
I could see you peeking from the end of the road
♪I wonder how much time is left?
♪I wonder how many more times can I still meet you in the spring...
♪At the hill by the riverside,
♪we're sitting beneath the shade of a tree
♪Again, just like yesterday, beneath the blooming flowers,
♪We're now forgetting to even breathe,
♪And it's too much work to even blink
♪There's no mistaking it; this storm of flowers scattering about right now
♪Is the spring thief
♪Today, still, time is being carried away by the wind,
♪And it's too much work to even stand up
♪The sky can be seen between the falling flowers
♪A spring storm is happening, still
♪～
♪Today, I'll go to see you as well
♪Then I'll sit beneath the shade of a tree
♪And let out a sigh
♪The flowers have stopped blooming
♪I'll go to see you again tomorrow
♪Spring is coming to an end
♪Time is fluttering down as if it's leaving behind
traces of the days we spent together
♪There aren't enough words out there to sing of love
♪It's too much work to even make them rhyme
♪There's no way things like words can convey the blossoming present
♪Gently falling, we're now forgetting even our voices
♪And it's too much work to even blink
♪Only the two of us are here to watch the cherry blossoms
♪And I'm begging for the spring storm to not stop just yet
♪Just a little bit left
♪I can now count the ones left
♪Two flowers left
♪Just one more flower left
♪Only the leaves are left now, gently falling
♪Right now, spring has come to an end
｢Algernon｣
♪～
♪Why did you give me my heart?
♪Why did you paint my eyes?
♪Greater than the sky,
swallowing the winds that sweeps away the clouds
♪My eyes are seeing a dream once again
♪Still on barefoot…
♪You're slowly changing, ever so slightly
♪As if watching a loaf of bread gradually puff up
♪You're slowly running
♪Staying unafraid of the long maze ahead
♪Why did you give me my name?
♪Why did you make me my hands?
♪Bigger than the sea,
swallowing the waves that even washes away the sand
♪These little hands were still staring far off into the distance
♪A single yawn…
♪We're slowly falling asleep
♪For a very long time,
♪in the center of our minds, a large tree grows
♪We're slowly walking through the roots
♪So that we won't be afraid of the long maze ahead
♪I wonder if one day I'll ever meet the person
that I've always struggled to catch up with
♪I wonder if one day I'll freeze up
behind a wall that I couldn't get past
♪I wonder if one day you'll end up giving up as well
♪You're slowly changing
♪You're slowly changing...
♪We're slowly forgetting, ever so slightly
♪As if staring at a tower slowly crumbling
♪We're slowly falling asleep
♪Slowly falling asleep…
♪You're slowly changing, ever so slightly
♪As if you're a shade growing in the middle of that tree
♪You're slowly running
♪Staying unafraid of the long maze ahead
♪While certainly being lost in it.
♪～
This is a series of pictures
of mysterious animals
that visted my home.
After midnight,
they would sit near my piano
and dance strange dances.
There was a mysterious charm to them.
They inspired me to create
this series of ten paintings.
I certainly hope that you enjoy them.
It was time for my exhibition.
I have a small sheet of paper in my hands.
It's a small postcard-size sheet
outlining the solo exhibition.
There were a few people
inside the small exhibition space
in a renovated room of a building.
Still, I feel
a strange sense of satisfaction.
Hello.
Well, if it isn't my landlord.
I see you've come. Thank you.
Please, enjoy.
(Woman) May I have one?
I hear a voice.
I see a once familiar face.
She's the girlfriend
I broke up with a while back.
Nice to see you. I appreciate
all your help with this.
(Ex-girlfriend) No problem.
The pictures are good.
I just wanted to lend you a hand.
You seem pretty busy lately.
(Ex-girlfriend) Yes.
Since I plan exhibitions while working,
I don't have much time.
But I enjoy it. It's what I want to do.
I stop myself before saying,
」You haven't changed.」
People seem as if they haven't changed,
but everyone changes.
Time doesn't pass only for me.
She looks at the paper in her left
hand,while my eyes are glued
to the ring on her ring finger.
Well, anyway... Enjoy.
(Ex-girlfriend) Yes. I'm hoping
this will be a good exhibition for you.
There's nothing special
I can say about the exhibition.
It lasted for a few weeks
and ended without incident.
One big development was that offers
were made on some of the paintings.
After much deliberation,
I kept the cat picture, and sold the rest.
(Ex-girlfriend) Nice work.
Oh, thank you.
(Ex-girlfriend) How was the exhibition?
It was great.
It's good to hear people's
reactions in person.
And I think I made some connections.
But best of all,
I got a job offer to paint.
After seeing this, they wanted to work with me.
(Ex-girlfriend) Really?
And I sold several paintings.
Not just of the dancing animals,
but some of my old paintings too.
(Ex-girlfriend) That's fantastic!
I told you about them before.
They're based on dreams of scenes
from a previous life.
Remember? You said you didn't like them.
(Ex-girlfriend) I remember those.
But that's not what I meant
when I said that.
I never said that I didn't like them.
Huh?
(Ex-girlfriend)
I just said they were dull.
I said, for a picture to be
accessible to people,
it's better if there's something
interesting about it.
Being dull doesn't affect
the quality of the painting.
Even if the setting's commonplace,
the painting will still have its own
unique value.
Even paintings
nobody buys are great paintings.
Come to think of it, she's probably right.
Painting is my livelihood,
so she was just giving me some
helpful advice.
She wasn't judging me.
What was it that possessed me?
That's a great thought.
Who said it? It really encouraged me.
(Ex-girlfriend) You said it.
Have you forgotten what you once said?
You haven't changed a bit.
I'm at a loss for words.
Bathed in the evening light
streaming in through the window,
she laughs mischievously.
The ring on her ring finger sparkles.
(Ex-girlfriend)
We'll say bye here. Thank you.
Okay. I've got to get back
to clean up anyway.
(Ex-girlfriend)
Hang in there.
I'll send you the final paperwork later.
Okay.
(Ex-girlfriend)
So, are you glad you did it?
It really feels like
these are my first
interesting paintings in a while.
I've gotten work too.
My future seems bright.
It's all thanks to those animals.
(Ex-girlfriend) You're so deadpan,
I can't tell when you're kidding.
Oh, sorry.
(Ex-girlfriend) I think it's
a great concept though.
Animals are cute and accessible.
The paintings had a coherent theme
and were easy on the eyes.
And it was quite amusing, too.
What was?
(Ex-girlfriend) Those animals
kind of resemble you.
Really?
Do I look that much like an animal?
How can I phrase it? Your expressions,
your mannerisms. Your aura.
Like that cat.
It looks just like you
when you play the piano.
Eyes closed, looking upward
with your nose poking into the air.
The piano?
(Ex-girlfriend) Yes. The piano.
Dancing animals...
This is a series of paintings
of mysterious animals
that visted my home.
After midnight,
they would sit near my piano
and dance a strange dance.
A strange dance...
It looks just like you
when you play the piano...
(Piano plays)
No, maybe it's the other way around.
Was I mistaken?
They weren't dancing.
Maybe they wanted to play the piano...
♪～(Piano Sonata 」Moonlight」)
I stand before the piano.
Moonlight illuminates the piano keys.
As I look at myself in the mirror
out of the side of my eye,
I slowly lower my arms to play.
That melody I have played many times,
Beethoven's Piano Sonata No. 14.
I see myself in the mirror.
My body moves as I play the piano keys.
And it looks as if I'm dancing
a strange dance.
♪～