A strange dance...
A strange...
dance...
I guess...
I recall the image of a bird
spreading its wings.
The bird looks at its reflection
in a puddle.
Wet with water, its feathers
gleam faintly.
Perhaps it flew through trees
laden with morning dew.
Even before the sun had fully risen,
its rays shone upon the bird's wings,
making them glisten so beautifully.
The bird in the puddle shakes its body,
and I can clearly see every drop
that is shaken off.
That's right. It's so crystal clear.
Many such sights exist in my mind.
I could say that I paint pictures
to download what's in my head.
There's a strange reality
in the panoramas of my mind.
And the resulting pictures
are just landscapes, so to speak.
Up until now, they haven't sold so well.
It was sunny outside.
I grabbed an empty paint tube
from the desk
and threw it in the bin,
dust scattering.
Caught in the spring sunlight
streaming through the window,
the particles sparkled,
as they swirled and danced.
Despite the beautiful weather,
my mood is dark.
Over the past few weeks, I've struggled
to paint anything meaningful.
It's not that I can't.
I just don't have the motivation.
I find myself alternating between
my bed and the canvas.
It's frustrating.
Birds.
(Bird chirping)
I envy birds.
They always seem to be having fun,
and have a reason to live
without even working.
See.
(Sound of bird song and flapping wings)
It's time to play that piece.
♪～(Piano Sonata 」Moonlight」)
(Cat meowing)
」Moon and Cat Dance」
♪～(Piano Sonata 」Moonlight」)
｢Bremen｣
♪～
♪Hey, no need to think.
♪We can't understand each other with empty talk.
♪Let‘s just ride this sound for now.
♪I want to keep it in my heart.
♪Our bodies are achromatic, laid back.
♪Just grooving with the swelling sound of rain.
♪Shall we live together forever
♪in a corner of this night?
♪～
♪Hey, we can be good-for-nothing.
♪It was you who said so and asked me out.
♪It's not fun when you're just logical.
♪Do you still hate to waste your time?
♪Vacuum-packing the scenery of us parading.
♪Grooving with the sound of stomping feet.
♪As if we were the town musicians of Bremen,
♪we march on, just the two of us.
♪Now, inhale and exhale real quick.
♪Singing is the best we can do.
♪How about laughing, why not join me?
♪I'm singing a song of love.
♪Ha haha.
♪Taking it easy is the best we can do.
♪Nothing in this world is worth dying for.
♪What shall we do tomorrow?
♪If you have time, let's understand each other.
♪～
♪Hey, no need to think.
♪Your cells have started dancing.
♪Let's just ride this sound for now.
♪It's okay if you can't.
♪Backpacking in the scenery of memories.
♪Grooving with the murmur of the spring wind.
♪Let's keep on singing together.
♪If you have time, why don't we do some loving?
♪Now, inhale and do it aloud.
♪Singing is the best we can do.
♪I can't complain about being laughed at.
♪Everything is just wrong. See?
♪Ha haha.
♪Taking it easy is the best we can do.
♪It's not easy to pretend to be a fool.
♪The lyrics are almost the same,
so you can skip the third verse.
♪～
♪Now, inhale and exhale real quick.
♪Hey, let me have your heart, just for today.
♪Singing is the best we can do. Am I wrong?
♪Are you all laughing at me? Say it.
♪Taking it easy is the best we can do.
♪Let's run away if life is killing you.
♪In a few years, nobody would remember anything.
♪Let's keep singing while wheezing.
♪Can you move? Why not join me?
♪I'm singing a song of love.
♪Ha haha.
♪Taking it easy is the best we can do.
♪Nothing in this world is worth dying for.
♪What shall we do tomorrow?
♪If you have time, let's laugh together
♪and understand each other in the meantime.
♪～
｢Rain with Cappuccino｣
♪Words that turned grayish white
♪remind me of the color of cappuccino.
♪No excuses. Leave them by the window.
♪There are just too many.
♪～
♪Hearts that turned grayish white
♪remind me of the color of cappuccino.
♪No excuses. Let's gulp down the cappuccino,
♪pretending to be just joking.
♪Now the rain flows as if wavering.
♪Drowning in the flowers that bring us a storm,
♪I wish for a memory that never lets you fade away.
♪Please, please,
♪please, so that you wouldn't overflow.
♪～
♪I wait for the waves at the coast as the setting sun
♪reflects red light on the window.
♪August in Visby, the roaring sea.
♪I wait in vain. A sea breeze is all I have.
♪Whiteness of the flowers that swam through summer,
the evening rain.
♪Drowning in the night that flows by,
♪I wish for a flower that never lets anyone fade away.
♪Please, please,
♪please, place it inside of my heart.
♪～
♪Something has been wrong with me.
♪I want you to tell me just one way to live,
♪but Ino longer have anything to give in return.
♪If you have no answer, just one word will do.
♪I don't get it.
♪I really don't get it.
♪Now the rain flows as if wavering.
♪Drowning in the flowers that bring us a storm,
♪I write songs so that you wouldn't fade away.
♪Please, please,
♪please, let them stay in my memory.
♪Another summer has passed,
♪with a flower held in my heart.
♪Behind my teary eyelids,
♪I hold this song so that you wouldn't fade away.
♪Please,
♪please, so that you wouldn't overflow.
♪～
(Sigh)
Something is lacking in your paintings.
That's what she said that day.
My ex-girlfriend who broke up with me
and left this place.
She's a promoter who works mostly on
small exhibitions in the city.
According to her, she said,
」Your pictures look like photos.」
Not because they are drawn precisely.
But because they are like copies of
scenery that can be found anywhere.
They're just... not interesting.
Her eyes were right.
People aren't touched by pictures drawn
without any thought.
Truth is, I've been content
being an unsuccessful artist,
barely ever drawing pictures.
Night has come.
Ultimately, I was never inspired
and spent the day aimlessly.
Maybe I need a change of scenery.
(Wind)
When I open the window,
a warm breeze blows in.
The moonlight shines down
between the clouds.
It sneaks inside through the window
and dances off the piano keys like a fish.
There's a perfect song for this feeling.
It's a piano sonata
that even an amateur like me can play.
♪～(Piano Sonata 」Moonlight」)
(Bird chirping)
(Wings fluttering)
A bird.
Hey.
Go on.
What's wrong. Go.
It was a small canary.
It stares at me with tiny,
black, beady eyes.
Its beak is round and pointed,
like a peanut.
It stands, its feet sticking out of its yellow
feathers, grasping the window sill.
Go on.
Oh well. Whatever. A tiny spectator.
Ah...
I always sit at the piano the same way.
I put my hands on the keys.
I check the position of the notes.
I place my foot on the pedals.
I sit up straight and raise my face.
Then I tense my arms.
♪～(Piano Sonata 」Moonlight」)
(Wings fluttering)
(Clears throat)
♪～(Piano Sonata 」Moonlight」)
(Wings fluttering)
The canary spreads its wings.
♪～(Piano Sonata 」Moonlight」)
It opens them slowly,
goes off balance, then closes them.
♪～(Piano Sonata 」Moonlight」)
I try playing a single long note.
(Piano plays)
(Sound of flapping wings)
It spreads its wings wide.
This time, I play a note, short and quick.
(Piano plays)
(Wings fluttering)
It flaps its wings then quickly stops.
I blink my eyes.
Have I finally lost my mind?
The canary stares at me
with its beady, black eyes.
♪～(Piano Sonata 」Moonlight」)
The canary spreads its yellow wings wide.
With the moonlight shining on it,
it glows faintly.
It flutters its wings,
as if it is dancing a waltz
to my poor piano playing.
Hah...
I smile without thinking.
On a whim,
I grab the sketchbook
and pencil from the music stand.
The canary stands there without moving.
I think, 」This is the first time
I've drawn a living canary.」
The night draws on.
Even the next day,
I sit before the canvas
scratching my head.
As always,
I don't feel as if I can draw a thing.
But I think I drew
an interesting sketch yesterday.
Well, it's just a drawing of a canary.
I don't think I can use it for anything.
I stand up and stretch.
Then, I thought about
the canary who flew off
somewhere after last night.
I open the window and look
at the sea far away.
(Sound of the sea breeze)
The sea breeze is blowing.
I imagine the yellow wings that have flown
(Sound of the sea breeze)
so very far away.
｢Goodbye Molten｣
♪～
♪With the book I borrowed in one hand,
♪I walk along the sidewalk by the river.
♪Two more pages and I'll get to the ending.
♪I don't want to know what lies ahead.
♪～
♪A boy riding on a goose's back
♪flies on and on toward the north.
♪His buddy is a goose named Molten.
♪That's the novel I'm reading.
♪Goodbye, Molten.
♪We used to try and see if we could fly.
♪We opened our arms and jumped high,
♪knowing that nothing would happen.
♪Goodbye, Molten.
♪You laughed as you rolled over.
♪Catching a faint smell of earth,
♪I almost got choked up inside.
♪Summer was already there.
♪～
♪With sadness as an asset,
♪I walk along the street in early summer.
♪Two more pages and I'll get to the ending.
♪I don't want to know what lies ahead yet.
♪Chasing you who got slightly taller,
♪I would run toward our favorite hill.
♪Just like a goose flying in the sky,
♪we would open up our arms.
♪Good bye, Molten.
♪We still tried to see if we could fly
♪just because we didn't want to know
that we were not special.
♪Goodbye, Molten.
♪You laughed as you rolled over,
♪looking like you had no idea
♪that we were growing up.
♪Summer was already there.
♪～
♪You'd grow even taller.
♪Someday you'd be far away.
♪We'd get separated little by little
♪like growing branches.
♪With the faded book in one hand,
♪I walk along the street I used to know.
♪From that hill, I'm a few hundred steps away.
♪I see someone standing there.
♪Goodbye, Molten.
♪I notice you were still trying to fly
♪with bright eyes,
♪just like the way you used to be.
♪Goodbye, Molten.
♪I think I know now, because we can't fly,
we're precious all the more.
♪A faint smell, I almost get choked up inside.
♪You've been watching me
♪with a smile that had never faded.
♪Summer is already here.
♪～
♪With the faded book in one hand,
♪I walk along the sidewalk by the river.
♪One more page and I'll get to the ending.
♪Now I turn the last page.
♪Goodbye, Molten.
｢Matasaburo｣
♪～
♪Stepping into a puddle,
♪you give a big yawn.
♪I want you to bring a terrible storm,
♪strong enough to blow this sky away.
♪I've been waiting for the wind
♪because monotonous life must be such a bore.
♪I've been waiting for the wind.
♪Let it blow hard through green leaves.
♪Blow off everything, even words.
♪And leave everyone speechless
♪by swallowing and carrying us all away.
♪Doddo-do, dodoh-do
♪～
♪So, is it true that you bring a storm?
♪As I asked with my eyes wide open,
♪you said to me bluntly,
♪」The world is my oyster.」
♪I've been waiting for the wind
♪because the society I fit in is way too uncomfortable.
♪」Then let it rain even harder!
♪Let the wind blow this feeling away.」
♪Let it blow hard through green leaves.
♪Throw away anything and everything.
♪If we remain this way,
♪we'll soon forget even who we are.
♪Blow off the green walnuts.
♪Blow off the sour quinces.
♪Blow harder, terribly harder.
♪Bring the wind to destroy this city.
♪Blow, blow hard through green leaves.
♪Throw away anything and everything.
♪Our sadness, our dreams, blow everything away,
♪Matasaburo
♪It's a long road ahead.
♪Now I see words are your wind.
♪Just leave everyone speechless
♪by swallowing and carrying us all away.
♪Doddo-do, dodoh-do
♪～
A single deer stares at me.
I stand beneath a tree with red blossoms.
I am holding a small box.
I realize that this is a dream.
(Sigh)
I think it's like my girlfriend
once said long ago.
My pictures are not interesting.
They lack any kind of appeal.
In creative work,
the message alone isn't everything.
If you want a picture to sell,
it needs to tell a story.
Unless your picture
has something that says, 」Look at me,」
it will never touch other people's hearts.
As a child, I was better at art
than with people.
Come to think of it, I still want to draw
what I wanted to then.
I have a very clear picture
of a scene in my mind.
Whenever I want to draw,
that comes to mind first.
A road where sunlight shines
between the trees.
A shopping arcade at sunset.
A bench and a church.
A town in a foreign country.
Rain on a cafe terrace.
It's so clear, it's annoying.
I can even see clearly each leaf
in an unfamiliar landscape.
I output it onto the canvas
without making a single change to it.
My drawings are not interesting.
(Sigh)
Another day has ended.
I light a cigarette
and place my hands on
the window sill as I exhale.
Then I feel something slimy
on my fingertips.
Yuck.
I see something light green.
(Frog croaking)
It's a frog.
I don't like these kinds of things.
Hey. Go away. Get out.
Don't make me say,
」Leap frog out of here.」
Hurry up. Get out.
I have a strange sense of
déjà vu as I shoo it away.
I feel as if I did
something similar before.
Oh well. Whatever.
Whoa!
(Frog croaking)
The thing came inside.
Give me a break, would you?
Hey, this isn't your home, you know.
Go on. Get out.
(Clicks tongue)
I finally realize why I feel this déjà vu.
It's that canary that showed up one day.
This thing has
that same strange impudence.
I give up and drop my arms,
striking the piano keys.
(Piano sound)
The frog twitches.
I tentatively raise my index finger
and press a key again.
It's a G note.
(Piano plays)
The frog slowly lifts its body.
I play the key again, and the frog moves.
I pull out the chair and sit down again.
Then I play the melody from 」Moonlight.」
♪～(Piano Sonata 」Moonlight」)
With its body still lifted,
it raises its arms.
On a whim,
I grab the sketchbook and pencil again.
I sketch the figure of the still frog
with its head held high
with my pen.
Though it's an ordinary frog,
it's almost as if
it has a mysterious allure to it.
I draw, and then I play the piano again.
I draw and play, play and draw.
It's figure is now in my sketchbook.
The frog's arms slowly wander in the air,
as if it is looking for something.
I can smell the night sea breeze.
The frog lifts its nose high
and flaps it little green arms.
It looked as if it was dancing
a strange dance.
｢Howl At The Moon｣
♪～
♪Howling at the moon by the roadside,
♪a shadow walks through the town.
♪Not knowing what it's like to be full,
♪the night slips into the depth.
♪I find myself in a crowd of people,
♪all are staring at my face.
♪What do you know about me?
♪I ask them pretending to be a beast.
♪I want to throw out the whole thing.
♪I want you to tell me that I'm alive.
♪Sing like howling at the moon, ah,
♪how brilliant.
♪I want to crush the earth with an ice pick
♪and fill it with my malice.
♪Sing like howling at the moon,
♪ah, and you can be selfish, act as you wish.
♪～
♪The pale moon by the roadside.
♪」Where is it?」 I hear people say.
♪I wonder if anyone can see
♪this ugly beast.
♪Turn towards the direction they point at.
♪Keep moving without a face.
♪Something is staring at me
♪from that shadow of the harbor.
♪I don't believe in the whole thing.
♪Nobody expects anything from you.
♪Sing like howling at the moon, ah,
♪how brilliant.
♪I want to dip a hard pen in the moon
reflected on a lake to draw a line on the waves.
♪Sing like howling at the moon, ah,
♪how glamorous.
♪Go with the flow of time.
♪～
♪Everyone thinks I'm a poor sick guy,
♪I know that!
♪～
♪I want to throw out the whole thing.
♪No, I'm not done with violating the world.
♪Sing like howling at the moon,
♪ah, how brilliant.
♪I want you to crush my skull with an ice pick
♪and fill it with lukewarm soup.
♪Sing like howling at the moon,
♪ah, you, a beast in the back of my throat,
♪and this world will be all yours.
♪～
♪Howl at the moon by the roadside.
｢451｣
♪～
♪Looking at that sun
♪burning so deeply,
♪I notice a small fire around my chest.
♪Then a passerby says out loud,
♪」Look at that weirdo,」 with a laugh.
♪My fingertip touches a piece of paper
and finally puts it on fire.
♪Now catch fire and burn,
♪burn, burn,
♪burn, burn.
♪Love the joy.
♪Now sublimate and dance,
♪dance, dance,
♪dance.
♪～
♪There, see the faces of people gathering around
♪looking for the intent of the flameI spread.
♪Look at those weirdos.
♪See how they raise their voices
♪and lose their heads over a mere flame.
♪Burn, make it fast, amid booming angry shouts.
♪Let the stack of paper burn red and bright.
♪Ah, what a bother,
♪now burn, burn, burn,
♪burn, burn.
♪Love the sadness too.
♪Now set fire and dance,
♪dance, dance,
♪dance.
♪～
♪Touch to put it out, touch to put it out.
♪Touch to open my heart's window.
♪Burn fast and show the ashes.
♪The soul smoldering deep inside—
♪Now make it catch fire and burn,
♪burn, burn,
♪burn, burn.
♪Love and burn with jealousy!
♪Now set fire and burn,
♪burn, burn,
♪burn, burn.
♪Love until you get fed up.
♪Now consume and dance,
♪dance, dance,
♪dance.
♪～
♪Now create and burn,
♪burn, burn,
♪burn.
(Phone ringing)
」That's like Kenji Miyazawa,」
my girlfriend says on the phone.
Isn't Kenji Miyazawa that author
from long ago in our textbooks?
」Yes. Haven't you read Gauche the Cellist?
Gauche is visited nightly
by an animal who asks him
to play his cello.」
Really?
」This is what that's like.
A serious guy like you
would never make that up,」
she adds with a laugh.
I murmur that it's no lie.
Gauche the Cellist...
Come to think of it,
I think I read it as a child.
It is similar. But it's also not.
The ones that visit me dance.
At night,
they come to my window and stare.
And they only react when I play the piano.
The frog raised and waved its arms,
and the canary spread its wings.
」Really?」
I thought she didn't believe me.
I guess that only makes sense.
Not long ago, a bat came to visit me.
(Bat cries)
It's not often you see a bat close-up.
So it was interesting.
(Bat cries)
It stood up straight on the window sill.
We think of bats being upside down.
(Bat cries)
But when it isn't upside down, it's more...
I guess you'd call it handsome.
It gave me the impression
that it was a gentleman.
」Really?」
There's more. Yesterday,
a rabbit was outside my window.
(Sound of a rabbit hopping)
I was suspicious, but when I played
the piano, it lifted its front legs
(Sound of a rabbit hopping)
and stretched out its arms,
swinging them back and forth.
(Sound of a rabbit hopping)
」That's cute.」
That was the fourth animal.
These aren't coincidences.
It made me wonder what it exactly was
these animals who came at night
were here to do.
When they moved their bodies
to the rhythm of the piano,
it was like they were trying to
express something.
That's it. This was a dance.
The spirit of a long-dead
regret-filled musician
is possessing the animals
and making them dance!
Might that be it?
」Well, even if I do believe your story,
were those really dances?
Maybe you just imagined they were dancing?」
You're wrong.
You won't understand unless you see.
」Really? Then maybe
I'll come over to watch sometime.」
I was a little shocked
and at a loss for words.
I'm not sure that's a good idea.
They don't come that often.
They hardly ever visit me.
」I'm just kidding,」 she said.
I realized she must believe
I'm lying even more now.
Anyway, that's what's been up.
I have no ideas, so I sketch them
to distract myself.
」I like it. The pictures
would go well with the story.
You should do children's books.」
You think? All I can do is draw.
」Drawings are all you need.」
Who would enjoy that?
」What? Nowadays, there are
many books of just pictures to imagine to.
What's more, a picture can say
just as much as words can.」
I'm impressed by what she says.
Who said that?
」You did.
Have you forgotten what you once told me?
You sure have changed,」
she says, poking fun at me.
I couldn't respond.
She was right.
A picture can say just as much as words.
All creations are nothing more
than words in a different form.
I was once so passionate
that I spoke words like that.
I had a passion that expresses more
than just skill and practice can.
Did I really say that?
I felt a little embarrassed
when saying that.
Then I hated myself
for feeling embarrassed.
I thought to myself, 」I think I understand
why she lost interest in me.」
I change the subject.
About that story, what happens at the end?
」Huh? You mean Gauche?」
Yeah.
She took a meaningful tone and said,
」He pondered about
the animals who visited,
wishing that he had treated them better.」
Really?
」Maybe you should be more careful.
Like they say, hindsight is 20/20.」
I realized she was being ironic.
Are you referring to us who broke up
because things didn't work out?
Well, anyway, I'll be careful.
I heard her laughing over the phone.
In the now silent room,
I pondered the words she said
just before hanging up the phone.
」Why not try drawing something
based on those animals?」
As I look at the sketches before me,
I imagine them standing there in my home.
♪Like flowers bloom, a touch of red on your cheeks.
｢Miyakoochi｣
♪Rippling waves on the sea.
♪You're on the shore, alone and just smiling.
♪Now, into a memory, I'm ousted from your heart.
♪～
♪Your humming, so beautiful.
♪Tomorrow, I know you're leaving.
♪I just heard a seagull cry.
♪Now I know that birds weep too.
♪When it dries somehow, it's time to say goodbye.
♪Buffeted by the summer wind,
you're covered in a faint shadow.
♪Just like that, flowers bloom on your blushing cheeks.
♪Rippling waves, a night on the sea.
♪You're on the shore, alone and just waving.
♪Now, into a memory, I'm ousted from your heart.
♪～
♪The morning glow, how beautiful.
♪The boat is about to leave, I know.
♪I just heard a seagull cry.
♪Now I know that you weep too.
♪Far from town, a head sea makes sounds.
♪Birds fly further away,
from tomorrow to the other side.
♪Down on the water, flowing into melancholy,
♪my longing for you follows the boat on the sea.
♪My fingers write with regret,
only how I feel about you.
♪Scattering memories set off
waves—ousted from your heart.
♪～
♪Away from the capital, the boat sails on.
♪Water flows, so does time.
♪I'll be a part of your memories.
♪Just the past behind you.
♪～
♪How I miss your blushing cheeks
♪and those agitated waves that come and go.
♪You're on the shore, alone and just smiling.
♪Now, into a memory, I'm—
♪Just like that, flowers bloom on your blushing cheeks.
♪Rippling waves, a night on the sea.
♪You're on the shore, alone and just waving.
♪Now, sayonara, I‘m ousted from your heart.
♪～
♪Floating in the night sky,
｢Cloudless｣
♪the moon like a jellyfish just burst.
♪When I look behind the bus stop,
♪I find you from that summer— in my head.
♪～
♪It's just that.
♪Shrine gate. Parched clouds.
♪The smell of summer brushing against our cheeks.
♪Until becoming grow-ups, you know,
♪we can keep aiming too high.
♪When tired from playing,
let's just watch the sky behind the bus stop.
♪Summer will be over soon,
♪but definitely we'll remember.
♪Grown up without ever catching up.
♪A night blooms inside your pocket.
♪If I can't say it out, I'll be left alone.
♪That's okay, so I gave up already.
♪It's just that.
♪～
♪Summer day. Parched clouds.
♪Downy cherry. Rusted signs.
♪Inside my memory, it always smells like summer.
♪Photographs are just scraps of paper.
♪Memories are nothing more than a pile of dust.
♪I can't grasp that,
♪so I keep my mouth shut.
♪A stone in a summer field,
♪where you eternally rest— in my memory.
♪Grown up without ever looking up.
♪I can't catch up. May your sky be always cloudless.
♪I walked up the hill, still unable to say it out.
♪A night is blooming on our shadows.
♪～
♪Grown up without ever looking up.
♪Clap your hands as you please.
♪Walking up a hill as the sun goes down,
♪our shadows—
♪Grown up without ever catching up.
♪A night blooms inside your pocket.
♪Without saying it out, we're as one anyway.
♪That's enough now, I guess.
♪I'm relishing the memory of you, it's just that.
♪～
♪It's just that.
｢Chinokate｣
♪～
♪The glass that swallowed the setting sun
♪looks like ruby.
♪Left unfinished,
it puts Saturday's feel of everyday life
♪on the table.
♪Those white flowers in the vase.
♪I guess they withered because of their kindness.
♪They were really precious to me, though,
♪it's about time to change them.
♪Oh, the setting sun.
♪It's really beautiful.
♪Is there a map showing
♪what's ahead and further on?
♪I wonder if you'll ever get lost.
♪That's okay.
♪No need to be changed.
♪Let's throw away what we really didn't need,
♪the sofa, and the books too,
♪and go out to the town.
♪～
♪Our hearts were supposed to be in our heads.
♪But something went wrong,
♪and they're in the text now.
♪Those white flowers in the vase.
♪I guess they withered before I knew it.
♪If they were so precious,
♪I shouldn't have bought them in the first place.
♪Oh, petals fell.
♪They're still beautiful.
♪Are you bound by the dream that
♪you've always wanted to live out?
♪If only you had a bit of courage
to say you can give it up.
♪Let's throw away what we really wanted,
the bag and the pen too,
♪and go out to the town.
♪～
♪You wanted me, but
♪I threw away that part of me
♪even though it was really precious.
♪Now it comes back to mind.
♪Those white flowers in the vase.
♪I didn't even notice they'd withered.
♪Now I know what was really precious
♪was the one who would change the flowers.
♪Oh, wait.
♪So you're really going.
♪Is there a map showing
♪what's ahead and further on?
♪I wonder if you'll ever get lost.
♪That's okay.
♪No need to be changed.
♪Let's throw away what we really didn't need,
♪the sofa, and the books too.
♪That's okay.
♪Is there a big light that keeps
illuminating your night?
♪I wonder if you're still going.
♪That's okay.
♪No need to be changed.
♪When you have read all,
♪please open your eyes.
♪Let's throw away this book
and go out to the town.
♪～
(Sound of insect wings)
I hear wings.
Something flies in through
the open window.
(Sound of insect wings)
It's a flying insect.
Perhaps a kind of stag beetle.
It has two short pincers.
♪～(Piano Sonata 」Moonlight」)
I rush to get my sketchbook.
One night, I see a chameleon.
As I play the piano,
I watch its tail hanging from
(The sound of a chameleon tail
tapping the piano top)
the piano top as it swings
in time with the rhythm.
(The sound of a chameleon tail
tapping the piano top)
Sometimes,
the tip of its curled tail extends,
(The sound of a chameleon tail
tapping the piano top)
and its shadow traces
the black keys of the piano,
swaying back and forth
like the surface of waves.
I'm used to it now.
I don't care what comes anymore.
(Tapping on window)
One night, I hear
the sound of tapping on the window.
It was a beautiful night
with a waning moon.
I listen closely.
There is also a strange sound,
like of a poorly fitted door closing.
(Sound of something creaking)
It's a deer.
A stag is sitting there.
It's a stag with horns
and a beautiful coat.
It's lying curled up
just outside the window,
lifting its head and looking at me.
I catch a whiff of what I once smelled
in a cowshed on a farm.
(Tapping on the window)
No way. This time it's impossible.
(Tapping on window)
Oh, give me a break.
I can hear the deer's breathing.
(Sigh)
I finally give up,
and back away toward the piano.
I play a single note
and hear that creaking door sound.
(Sound of something creaking)
There's no doubt.
That is the sound it makes.
As if trying to escape reality,
I am impressed by the sound it makes.
I begin playing the introduction,
which I have played often.
♪～(Piano Sonata 」Moonlight」)
(Deer's moan)
Please, try to be silent.
Try not to moan.
(Tapping on window)
None of that either.
The deer watches me
with a gaze
that's as black as the deep night,
a mysterious color that draws you in.
♪～(Piano Sonata 」Moonlight」)
The deer closes its eyes.
Then it opens and closes
its mouth again and again.
It raises its head
and stretches its nose
as if to approach the window.
Occasionally, its red tongue peeks out.
I can hear the deer's breathing.
For some reason,
the sound has a nostalgic feel.
After finishing the introduction,
I start playing 」Moonlight」 again.
The deer lowers its head back down,
opens its eyes, and looks at me.
This is the only part I can play.
The deer looks at me.
It's as if he's saying, 」That's fine.」
I start playing 」Moonlight」 again.
I play only the introduction,
as if going round and round
in the same place.
(Waves)
(Sound of a toy piano)
(Owl hooting)
I found this on the beach.
Some one must have tossed it out.
It made me wonder
if it would dance
if it wasn't played on my piano.
I see feathers sticking out of the pot.
I bet I'm the only human
who's ever carried an owl in a pot.
It's dark black eyes look at me.
There are yellow circles like egg yolks
covering those black eyes,
like crescent moons.
I open my sketchbook
and start drawing with my pencil.
The owl in the pot stands there
with a puzzled look.
Long ago, I often used to dream of
becoming a bird.
Oh. Not a bird like you.
A bird that spreads its wings wide.
Its wings shining faintly with the dew
that wet its wings
as it flew between the trees.
The sunlight before it has fully risen is
almost annoyingly beautiful.
My body shivers.
Then, I fly
toward the sun.
Eventually, I run out of energy and fall.
When I woke up, I remembered it clearly.
When I drew it on paper,
I got a mysteriously good feeling.
Now that I think about it,
that was the first picture I drew.
(Sound of a toy piano)
I doubt I am any different than then.
Or rather, I have not changed.
I am better at using a brush and pen,
but that is all.
Only my sketching is better.
Only my perspective is more accurate.
Only my lines are more beautiful.
What is in my head, what is before me,
I am merely copying what I see there.
When asked if that's what I want to draw,
I tilt my head.
I am empty.
I sometimes become afraid.
Is what I am doing actually
not much different than
what a camera does?
(Sound of a toy piano)
When I think too much about things
like that, I play this song.
Piano sonata 14, the Moonlight Sonata.
I love this song.
I was taught it when I was a child.
It clearly sounds like a depressing song,
but how can I put this...
Nobody has ever agreed with me on this,
but when I play this, I become incredibly
nostalgic.
My eyes meet the yellow crescent moons.
I don't care and keep playing the keys.
Every time the scratchy sound is played,
I see the owl fluffing its wings
in discomfort.
｢The Fifth Night｣
♪～
｢Snow Country｣
♪Coming out of the long tunnel on the border,
we find the snow country
♪taking on the stillness of
a bone-chilly night to lay white.
♪～
♪Casting a sidelong glance
at the snowy old townscape,
♪the snow county is just imbued with the memory
of the springtime with you.
♪My hesitation covers the moon
and it's dark like the bottom of the sea.
♪Sitting in a daze, we're looking at our own reflections
on the surface of the water.
♪～
♪Stretching over a dining table and a long bar,
the snow country is
♪just catching the scent of the stillness
of spring star flowers.
♪Your tears scatter in the wind and it's like
we're in the middle of the spring.
♪Sitting in a daze, we're looking at our own reflections
on the surface of the soup.
♪～
♪Our melancholy piles up day after day
and it looks like the snow country.
♪I beg you to hesitate. I hope you care too.
♪Until the snow melts.
♪Until the love is solved.
♪～
♪Coming out of the long tunnel on the border,
we found ourselves
♪taking on the stillness of a bone-chilly night
and tinged with white.
♪～
｢Whale｣
♪Your pectoral fins
♪swim by the window,
♪looking like melted
♪and softened amber.
♪The tip of your nose,
♪your dorsal fin and moustache,
♪and your quiet eyes look like
♪they belong to the night.
♪Talking, crying,
♪we were stroking the waves
♪as if feeling nostalgic for the land.
♪Drop your eyelids and cover your eyes.
♪Sleep tight so that you won't awake right away
♪with your breath spouting out.
♪Now swim deep, swim on
♪in the waves of your shallow sleep
♪falling into a white slumber.
♪Your chirping
♪and dappled sunlight on the sofa
♪remind me of the seashore
♪that swayed softly.
♪Laughing, weeping,
♪we are waiting for the waves
♪so that we can recall before long.
♪Travel through the waves and dive deep,
♪deeper and deeper until you suffocate
♪with your breath spouting out.
♪Now swim deep, swim on
♪with your long tail fin
♪laid down on the waves.
♪～
♪Talking, crying,
♪we were stroking the waves
♪hoping to see each other again someday.
♪Drop your eyelids and cover your eyes.
♪Sleep tight so that you won't awake from a dream
♪and forgive yourself already.
♪Now swim deep, swim on
♪in the waves of your shallow sleep
♪falling into a white slumber.
♪～
(Phone ringing)
Did you see the picture I sent?
What did you think?
Actually, I tried drawing
like you told me before.
When I used those animals
as a motif for my drawings,
it was unbelievably easy to draw them.
This series of pictures
is called 」Dancing Animals.」
I think
they've turned out really interesting.
Yeah.
Uh-huh.
Oh, uh...
Canary, rabbit, chameleon,
owl, leaf beetle, frog, bat,
and the deer.
Huh? No, seriously.
I was visited by a deer. A stag.
Yeah, I get it. It sounds unbelievable.
Yes, the first one is of a human...
I mean, humans are animals too,
so I just had to draw it.
The motif?
Uh, well...
Yeah?
Huh? An exhibition?
Where?
Oh, there.
Are you sure? I mean...
Wait. I'll do it.
This is a great chance. Sure.
This makes me so happy. Thank you.
I'll prep what I've drawn before
so they can be displayed too.
Sure. Let's meet so we can
talk things over face-to-face.
Okay. See you later.
This is a golden opportunity.
All right.
Let's do this!
｢Setting Sun｣
♪Our cheeks glow red by soft sunlight.
♪Setting sunbursts and it doesn't let our eyes open.
♪～
♪It's sad but it can't be helped.
♪My hands got wet in the sun.
♪Such unbearable brightness
♪made me feel lost on my way home.
♪Like falling,
♪the madder-colored sunlight hit me.
♪Just a little more
♪I could almost love a piece of myself.
♪But the setting sun didn't let my eyes open
before I knew it
♪in the quiet evening calm.
♪It's sad but it can't be helped.
♪My hands touched the sun.
♪Like burning with a feeble flame,
♪it scorched just my fingertips.
♪Like grapes hanging from a high branch,
♪it's unreachable, so don't you dare.
♪I wonder if I fell in love.
♪Like that setting sun,
♪if there's no reason for falling,
♪I'd rather—
♪～
♪Our cheeks glow red by soft sunlight.
♪Setting sun bursts and if it just lights up our way—
♪Then I could almost love a piece of myself.
♪I saw you smiling shyly at the setting sun.
♪In the quiet evening calm,
♪we can't even open our eyes.
｢Fireworks of Shoes｣
♪～
♪Hey, hey,
♪I want to say something, but I fall short of words
♪because I'm struck speechless.
♪So—
♪～
♪Hey, hey,
♪We remain silent, but we don't need words
♪because the eyes are so eloquent.
♪We forget things as a result of the bugs
starting to eat them.
♪In my memory, I see nothing but smiling faces.
♪In the color of dusk, we fly through the sky.
♪Fly on and even out of the atmosphere.
♪Right below, what looks smaller and smaller
♪is the city where you lived.
♪Flowers burst at the tip of my shoes.
♪Big flowers of fire burst into bloom.
♪I'll leave my whole heart here.
I thought so somehow.
♪I saw the summer like that.
♪～
♪Hey, hey,
♪I want to know you, but I can't make up my mind
♪because I'm sure you'll boast about it.
♪There's nothing to make me feel relieved,
♪but the sky is beautiful today as usual.
♪All the things I ate should be the price of my life.
♪It's too late for me and I can't even
be the nighthawk.
♪In the color of dawn, we dance in the sky.
♪It's nonsense to ask what to wish for.
♪I've grown up and forgotten.
♪My eyes that reflect you get in my way.
♪Far below, flowers boomed.
♪Big flowers of fire boomed.
♪Just hearing the sound makes me cry.
I thought so somehow.
♪I heard the summer like that.
♪～
♪Hey, hey,
♪I want to fly, but I don't know when to stop
♪because I know I'll look for you.
♪So—
♪In the color of dusk, we fly through the sky.
♪Fly on and even out of this planet's present state.
♪Right below, what became smaller
♪and vanished is the city where you lived.
♪Flowers burst in the summer sky.
♪Big flowers of fire burst into bloom.
♪I want to keep crying forever.
I thought so somehow.
♪The summer like that is gone.
♪～
Okay. I see.
Yes. I'll be careful.
Thank you always.
The exhibition? It's coming soon.
As a sign of gratitude, as my landlord,
can I invite you?
Oh, I see. Ha ha ha...
No, it's okay.
Yes. Okay.
Goodbye.
It's not easy living in this day and age.
Seems like I haven't painted for days.
Probably because I've been busy prepping.
(Cat meowing)
I hear a cat meowing somewhere.
I open the window and look outside.
Nothing there.
Oh well, whatever.
I leave the window open
and sit at the piano.
I touch the keys.
I begin playing the intro
to 」Moonlight.」
♪～(Piano Sonata 」Moonlight」)
After playing a while,
I hear something at the window.
A cat suddenly appears
and sits on the piano.
I watch the cat as I continue playing.
The cat raises its nose
into the air and stands up.
It closes its eyes,
as if listening to the notes.
I stop playing.
The cat stops moving.
It opens its eyes
and I see the tips of its hair moving.
I've been drawing pictures of you.
All of these here.
They're pretty fun, right?
I guess the landlord must have seen me.
He said he thought I'd been feeding
the animals.
When I told him the animals came
simply because I was playing the piano,
he looked at me as if I was mad.
So he told me he's taking back
the piano at the end of the month.
This belongs to the landlord.
His niece wants to learn,
so he's giving it to her.
Mind you, I'm sure there were
complaints about the noise, too.
This piano is going to disappear.
That means there's no reason
for you guys to keep coming.
I don't like it.
You're not disposable materials.
It's thanks to you, I made this art,
and I've been able to do
a solo exhibition.
I mean, you guys,
you come here to hear me play, right?
♪～(Piano Sonata 」Moonlight」)
The eyes of the cat sitting on
the piano meet mine.
I'm stunned.
The cats' eyes are
the color of the deep night.
They shimmer like the surface of water.
I feel as if I've seen this color before.
Sometime, long, long ago.
Somewhere.
What is this?
I felt something running down on my face.
(Sniffling)
Tears.
Overflowing tears.
The image of me
desperately wiping away my tears
can be seen in the mirror in the room.
The moonlight
gently illuminates the piano keys.
The cat quietly approaches me.
Then it puts its nose
against mine as if to kiss me.
The cat silently goes out the window.
This was the last time I ever saw them.
｢Left-Right Confusion｣
♪You rested your chin on your right hand.
♪I held a lukewarm mug with my left hand.
♪Your right eyebrow was slightly slated downward.
♪Morning rained down on us so much.
♪One is enough.
♪Just one peony flower that never falls.
♪Let it strike your heart
♪and make you so happy that you could
forget about your heart.
♪One is enough.
♪Through the confusing night without
knowing right from left,
♪I grope my way all alone in dead silence.
♪If only I could let you know a piece of that.
♪Your left eyebrow was slightly slated downward.
♪It's hard for me to recall.
♪It seems that I can't tell.
♪Your right hand held the novel that
you bought one day.
♪Or was it your left hand?
♪～
♪One is enough.
♪Just one piece of the sunlight in the night.
♪Strike your heart with such sentiment
♪that I could peek inside your heart.
♪One is enough
♪to show that you could grope your way
in a flurry of hail in summer
♪and that your eyes would never close.
♪～
♪I would peel off my heart from my body bit by bit
♪and hand it to you,
♪and you could have all of it, so—
♪Take the ruby out of my sword-hilt,
♪the sapphires out of my eyes.
♪Just leave the leaden heart by my side.
♪One is enough.
♪Just one peony flower that never falls.
♪Let it strike your heart
♪and make you so happy that you could forget
about the tears you shed.
♪A little is enough.
♪Just a little sunlight to
make the drizzle stop today.
♪A little is enough.
♪Let me leave a little part of
my shoeprint in your world.
♪Can you see? Your happiness could be
♪more than just one.
♪Through the confusing night without
knowing right from left,
♪you have a long way to grope from here.
♪I'm the only one who will never laugh about it.
♪If only I could let you know a piece of that.
♪No matter what I eat, everything is tasteless.
♪It feels like I've just lost my body.
♪Your heart and my heart
♪would be as one forever, I believed.
｢Spring Thief｣
♪～
♪Out of the elevated bridge,
I saw blue patches through clouds
♪During these warm days,
I've been just waiting for a wind to blow
♪Sitting in the shade of a tree
♪Something sticks to my cheek
♪Look up to see blossoms in bloom
and falling over me
♪Fluttering petals takes our breath away
♪Even blinking is a bother
♪Look, even today becomes the past tomorrow
♪Just wait for the wind
♪So now we're left speechless
♪Even saying goodbye is a bother
♪Just blossoms are fluttering down in sunlight
♪Now like spring confetti
♪～
♪The next day we're meeting up again
♪There're fewer people viewing blossoms
♪Spring scent is about to disappear
♪Seems like summer is coming again
♪Out of the elevated bridge,
I saw you at the end of the road
♪I wonder how much time is left
♪How much longer can I see spring?
♪On a riverside hill,
♪sitting in the shade of a tree
♪Bloosoms are in bloom today just like yesterday
♪Let them take our breath away
♪Even blinking is a bother
♪This storm blowing off the blossoms is
♪Literally a spring thief
♪The wind makes the time fly again today
♪Even standing up is a bother
♪Blue sky shows through the blossoms, fluttering
♪Still like spring confetti
♪～
♪Going to see you again today
♪And sit in the shade of a tree
♪I let out a sigh
♪Blossoms will be gone soon
♪Going to see you again tomorrow
♪Spring will soon be over
♪As if with reluctance, time flutters down
♪When I sing love, I fall short of words
♪Even rhyming is a bother
♪To this season in bloom,
I doubt words can ever do justice
♪Fluttering petals leaves us speechless
♪Even blinking is a bother
♪Nobody but us are here for the blossoms
♪Don't go just yet, spring confetti
♪For just a little longer
♪Only a few are left
♪Just two more flowers
♪Just one more to go
♪Only the leaves are left behind, fluttering
♪Now, spring is over
｢Algernon｣
♪～
♪I wonder why you gave me a heart.
♪Why did you draw eyes on my face?
♪Bigger than the sky,
swallowing the wind that carried the clouds,
♪my eyes were dreaming once again.
♪With bare feet,
♪you're changing slowly, only a little,
♪like watching a bread puff up little by little.
♪You keep on running slowly,
♪unafraid of what lies beyond the long maze.
♪I wonder why you gave me a name.
♪Why did you make hands for me?
♪Bigger than the ocean,
swallowing the wave that carried the sand,
♪my small hands were still gazing into the distance.
♪With a yawn,
♪we're falling asleep slowly,
♪for a long time to come,
♪walking slowly by the base of a big tree
♪that grows in the center of our heads
♪to be unafraid of what lies beyond the long maze.
♪Someday, will we meet the one
we can never catch up with?
♪Someday, will we flinch at a wall
that we can never clear?
♪Someday, will you give up on it too?
♪Slowly changing.
♪We're losing memories slowly,
only a little,
♪like watching a tower collapse little by little.
♪We're falling asleep slowly,
♪falling asleep slowly.
♪You're changing slowly, only a little,
♪like the shade growing in the center of that tree.
♪You keep on running slowly,
♪unafraid of what lies beyond the long maze,
♪losing your way sometimes, for sure.
♪～
This is a series of pictures
of mysterious animals
that visted my home.
After midnight,
they would sit near my piano
and dance strange dances.
There was a mysterious charm to them.
They inspired me to create
this series of ten paintings.
I certainly hope that you enjoy them.
It was time for my exhibition.
I have a small sheet of paper in my hands.
It's a small postcard-size sheet
outlining the solo exhibition.
There were a few people
inside the small exhibition space
in a renovated room of a building.
Still, I feel
a strange sense of satisfaction.
Hello.
Well, if it isn't my landlord.
I see you've come. Thank you.
Please, enjoy.
(Woman) May I have one?
I hear a voice.
I see a once familiar face.
She's the girlfriend
I broke up with a while back.
Nice to see you. I appreciate
all your help with this.
(Ex-girlfriend) No problem.
The pictures are good.
I just wanted to lend you a hand.
You seem pretty busy lately.
(Ex-girlfriend) Yes.
Since I plan exhibitions while working,
I don't have much time.
But I enjoy it. It's what I want to do.
I stop myself before saying,
」You haven't changed.」
People seem as if they haven't changed,
but everyone changes.
Time doesn't pass only for me.
She looks at the paper in her left
hand,while my eyes are glued
to the ring on her ring finger.
Well, anyway... Enjoy.
(Ex-girlfriend) Yes. I'm hoping
this will be a good exhibition for you.
There's nothing special
I can say about the exhibition.
It lasted for a few weeks
and ended without incident.
One big development was that offers
were made on some of the paintings.
After much deliberation,
I kept the cat picture, and sold the rest.
(Ex-girlfriend) Nice work.
Oh, thank you.
(Ex-girlfriend) How was the exhibition?
It was great.
It's good to hear people's
reactions in person.
And I think I made some connections.
But best of all,
I got a job offer to paint.
After seeing this, they wanted to work with me.
(Ex-girlfriend) Really?
And I sold several paintings.
Not just of the dancing animals,
but some of my old paintings too.
(Ex-girlfriend) That's fantastic!
I told you about them before.
They're based on dreams of scenes
from a previous life.
Remember? You said you didn't like them.
(Ex-girlfriend) I remember those.
But that's not what I meant
when I said that.
I never said that I didn't like them.
Huh?
(Ex-girlfriend)
I just said they were dull.
I said, for a picture to be
accessible to people,
it's better if there's something
interesting about it.
Being dull doesn't affect
the quality of the painting.
Even if the setting's commonplace,
the painting will still have its own
unique value.
Even paintings
nobody buys are great paintings.
Come to think of it, she's probably right.
Painting is my livelihood,
so she was just giving me some
helpful advice.
She wasn't judging me.
What was it that possessed me?
That's a great thought.
Who said it? It really encouraged me.
(Ex-girlfriend) You said it.
Have you forgotten what you once said?
You haven't changed a bit.
I'm at a loss for words.
Bathed in the evening light
streaming in through the window,
she laughs mischievously.
The ring on her ring finger sparkles.
(Ex-girlfriend)
We'll say bye here. Thank you.
Okay. I've got to get back
to clean up anyway.
(Ex-girlfriend)
Hang in there.
I'll send you the final paperwork later.
Okay.
(Ex-girlfriend)
So, are you glad you did it?
It really feels like
these are my first
interesting paintings in a while.
I've gotten work too.
My future seems bright.
It's all thanks to those animals.
(Ex-girlfriend) You're so deadpan,
I can't tell when you're kidding.
Oh, sorry.
(Ex-girlfriend) I think it's
a great concept though.
Animals are cute and accessible.
The paintings had a coherent theme
and were easy on the eyes.
And it was quite amusing, too.
What was?
(Ex-girlfriend) Those animals
kind of resemble you.
Really?
Do I look that much like an animal?
How can I phrase it? Your expressions,
your mannerisms. Your aura.
Like that cat.
It looks just like you
when you play the piano.
Eyes closed, looking upward
with your nose poking into the air.
The piano?
(Ex-girlfriend) Yes. The piano.
Dancing animals...
This is a series of paintings
of mysterious animals
that visted my home.
After midnight,
they would sit near my piano
and dance a strange dance.
A strange dance...
It looks just like you
when you play the piano...
(Piano plays)
No, maybe it's the other way around.
Was I mistaken?
They weren't dancing.
Maybe they wanted to play the piano...
♪～(Piano Sonata 」Moonlight」)
I stand before the piano.
Moonlight illuminates the piano keys.
As I look at myself in the mirror
out of the side of my eye,
I slowly lower my arms to play.
That melody I have played many times,
Beethoven's Piano Sonata No. 14.
I see myself in the mirror.
My body moves as I play the piano keys.
And it looks as if I'm dancing
a strange dance.
♪～